<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: windows | michael-mccracken.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/categories/windows/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-12T12:34:42-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael McCracken]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[That Windows feeling]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/09/that-windows-feeling/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-04T04:44:40-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/09/that-windows-feeling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this post more than a year ago. Not much has changed, and it&rsquo;s time to just let it out.</p>

<p>Uninvited dialogs popping to the front or stealing keyboard focus in OS X have been giving me <strong>that Windows feeling</strong> lately. It was part of the old Mac OS&rsquo;s comfortable &ldquo;I&rsquo;m in control&rdquo; feeling, and was always immediately noticeable using Windows &ndash; popups and splash screens everywhere.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s particularly bad with multiple monitors, when you may not notice that a dialog opened on the other monitor and is stealing all your keypresses, making the app you thought you were using seem unresponsive and rudely interrupting your work.</p>

<p>Here are just a few that I notice all the time:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Apple Backup: Every damn time it runs a backup I get an annoying alert, sometimes two if the media isn&rsquo;t ready when it wants to run. This is the one single situation that I can remember Retrospect&rsquo;s UI being better.</p></li>
<li><p>Apple Mail: If a message is sent but the SMTP server can&rsquo;t be contacted, the message pops back up with a sheet to pick a new server to be used until you change locations &ndash; a feature I endure daily to cope with my home ISP insisting I use their SMTP server. This window pops to the front and steals key focus, so if you&rsquo;re typing in another mail message, you lose letters.</p></li>
<li><p>Safari with GMail: sometimes GMail just pops to the front of the stack. I don&rsquo;t ever want a web page deciding that it needs to be in the front &ndash; what is going wrong here? (note, now that I use my WebMail app, this doesn&rsquo;t happen to me anymore…)</p></li>
<li><p>Safari also pops the download window up when it starts a download &ndash; good idea right? Not if it took a while to start the download and I&rsquo;m now editing something in a totally unrelated browser window&hellip;</p></li>
<li><p>Growl: Growl could be a solution to some of these problems, but it adds its own annoyance.  Just waving your pointer over a notification &ndash; or even having it sitting in the spot the notification appears at &ndash; steals key focus from the current app. I use a variety of sticky notifications that I have to click on, and so this happens to me all the time.</p></li>
<li><p>FileMerge: if it takes a while to open a merge and I&rsquo;ve moved away, it still pops the window to the front and takes key.</p></li>
<li><p>iTunes: changes to the music store status (like it finally loading a page), cause background windows to pop up in front of other iTunes windows. This doesn&rsquo;t happen in browsers, why here?</p></li>
<li><p>iTunes: A more debatable example is if your iPod battery is completely drained, it will charge for a while before bringing iTunes to the front at a random time when it&rsquo;s ready to sync. This is only if you&rsquo;ve already requested iTunes to be shown when you plug in your iPod, so maybe it&rsquo;s not their fault it annoys me.</p></li>
<li><p>Keychain security &ndash; because I have sensitive passwords on my laptop, my keychains lock when it sleeps, and time out. So I see a lot of the keychain password dialog, which steals key focus &ndash; even when it&rsquo;s invoked from an app in the background. Backup makes this happen regularly. The dialog is small enough that I often don&rsquo;t notice it on the other monitor.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If this annoys you too, share your examples in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows User]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/09/windows-user/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T15:18:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/09/windows-user</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been a Windows User for two weeks now. Since <a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/?p=64">my powerbook disk died</a>, I&rsquo;ve been working on a loaner Dell Lattitude with XP.</p>

<p>I get by. It&rsquo;s not as hard as I would have guessed. Most of my work these days just needs a decent terminal, and SSH from ssh.com (who knew there was a commercial SSH?) works OK. I don&rsquo;t understand why it doesn&rsquo;t save my keyboard preferences, but I muddle through.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m using <a href="http://www.washington.edu/pine/">pine</a> for email, and the lack of <a href="http://c-command.com/spamsieve">SpamSieve</a> is shockingly obvious. Sometimes control characters in spam emails garble the screen so badly that I can&rsquo;t tell what I&rsquo;m deleting.</p>

<p>Otherwise, I use Firefox, and Google calendar keeps my schedule. So far, I haven&rsquo;t missed my iCal integration applescripts (<a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/blosxom.pl/computers/mac/todoQuickSilver.html">new-todo-in-quicksilver</a>,
<a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/blosxom.pl/computers/mac/programming/ASiCal.html">new-event-from-email</a>, and <a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/?p=30">new-todo-from-email</a>), but I&rsquo;m sure I will if this goes on longer.</p>

<p>I miss the years of notes I had inVoodooPad. In its place, I&rsquo;ve been using emacs org-mode in a terminal. I like the outlining and todo/agenda gathering it can do, and wouldn&rsquo;t be opposed to similar features in VoodooPad. I&rsquo;d actually been using it in the weeks before my forced <em>switch</em>, but just for the todos.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve accidentally tried to print about a hundred times when editing text, expecting the old emacs shortcuts to be there. This is OK, though, because I can&rsquo;t configure printers.</p>

<p>There is a similar story for almost every key shortcut I want to use &ndash; I have no idea how to switch between tabs in Firefox, and when I did find out how to minimize windows from the keyboard (Alt-space, &lsquo;n&rsquo;), I wished I hadn&rsquo;t, because it only works in half of the programs I use.</p>

<p>One thing Windows does is make me want to give up earlier. I actually just don&rsquo;t care if I can&rsquo;t figure out a good way to do something. This is an exciting new feeling &ndash; I just give up and get back to work, and each time, I feel a little more like a real grownup. You know, how you feel after all your youthful dreams have died.</p>

<p>I get more done at work with Windows. I no longer install programs just to try them out (scary!), or hack on minor projects (no friendly tools built-in). Even just surfing around is just not as tempting, and I do less of it, both at work and at home. In moments of weakness, I have considered swapping my PowerBook for three pound Windows laptop, just so I can finish sooner and with better posture. I know I could never do it, but the thought lingers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
