<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (architecture)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 10:00:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for mid-March see scalable python around corners. And Future Spies on Facebook!</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/03/links-for-mid-march-see-scalable-python-around-corners-and-future-spies-on-facebook.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for March 18th through March 26th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/3/26/7-years-of-youtube-scalability-lessons-in-30-minutes.html"&gt;7 Years of YouTube Scalability Lessons in 30 Minutes&lt;/a&gt; - Notes from a PyCon talk about the very pragmatic design philosophy at YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/bkad/discoball"&gt;bkad/discoball * GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - shell tool to match and colorize lines of text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pragprog.com/book/kcdc/the-developer-s-code"&gt;The Pragmatic Bookshelf | The Developer's Code&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/news/how-to-see-around-corners-1.10258"&gt;How to see around corners : Nature News &amp;amp; Comment&lt;/a&gt; - And we thought the future was flying cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2012/03/19/cia_internet_of_things/page2.html"&gt;ARM's ultra-low-power fridge-puter chips: Just what the CIA ordered • The Register&lt;/a&gt; - Out of context interesting quote: "The spy boss was chiefly concerned with the huge amounts of data that can be collected from American citizens who intend to become CIA agents - in an age when parents set up Twitter and Tumblr accounts for their newborns, managing the identities of future operatives suddenly becomes non-trivial."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://reprog.wordpress.com/2012/02/27/who-needs-access-you-need-access/"&gt;Who needs access? You need access!&lt;/a&gt; - new site about open access to research aimed at lay people (I think)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>ARM</category><category>CIA</category><category>architecture</category><category>colorize</category><category>future</category><category>imaging</category><category>internet-of-things</category><category>laser</category><category>links</category><category>logging</category><category>openaccess</category><category>philosophy</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>programming</category><category>python</category><category>research</category><category>scalability</category><category>shell</category><category>spies</category><category>spycam</category><category>wisdom</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/03/links-for-mid-march-see-scalable-python-around-corners-and-future-spies-on-facebook.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links for December 13th through December 19th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/12/links-for-december-13th-through-december-19th.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for December 13th through December 19th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.patientslikeme.com/"&gt;Treatment and Side Effect Info from Patients Like You : PatientsLikeMe&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://insidehpc.com/2011/12/13/nvidia-opens-cuda-compiler-source-code/"&gt;NVIDIA open sources compiler for CUDA based on LLVM&lt;/a&gt; - tweeted by insideHPC at 12/13/11 7:19 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aosabook.org/en/index.html"&gt;The Architecture of Open Source Applications&lt;/a&gt; - Architects look at thousands of buildings during their training, and study critiques of those buildings written by masters. In contrast, most software developers only ever get to know a handful of large programs well--usually programs they wrote themselves--and never study the great programs of history. As a result, they repeat one another's mistakes rather than building on one another's successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book's goal is to change that. In it, the authors of twenty-five open source applications explain how their software is structured, and why. What are each program's major components? How do they interact? And what did their builders learn during their development? In answering these questions, the contributors to this book provide unique insights into how they think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a junior developer, and want to learn how your more experienced colleagues think, this book is the place to start. If you are an intermediate or senior developer, and want to see how your peers have solved hard design problems, this book can help you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.neverworkintheory.org/?p=197"&gt;An Empirical Comparison of the Accuracy Rates of Novices using the Quorum, Perl, and Randomo Programming Languages - It will never work in theory&lt;/a&gt; - We present here an empirical study comparing the accuracy rates of novices writing software in three programming languages: Quorum, Perl, and Randomo. The first language, Quorum, we call an evidence-based programming language, where the syntax, semantics, and API designs change in correspondence to the latest academic research and literature on programming language usability. Second, while Perl is well known, we call Randomo a Placebo-language, where some of the syntax was chosen with a random number generator and the ASCII table. We compared novices that were programming for the first time using each of these languages, testing how accurately they could write simple programs using common program constructs (e.g., loops, conditionals, functions, variables, parameters). Results showed that while Quorum users were afforded significantly greater accuracy compared to those using Perl and Randomo, Perl users were unable to write programs more accurately than those using a language designed by chance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>architecture</category><category>community</category><category>documentary</category><category>empirical-software-engineering</category><category>http://twitter.com/insideHPC/status/146761306207301633)</category><category>links</category><category>medicine</category><category>movies</category><category>opensource</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>productivity</category><category>programming</category><category>software</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/12/links-for-december-13th-through-december-19th.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 20:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>