<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (bibdesk)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/bibdesk.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How BibDesk generates Apple Help and a web manual</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/02/how-bibdesk-generates-apple-help-and-a-web-manual/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is something that had been on my old blog in 2006 and went away, so I'm reposting something I wrote to the macsb list a few years ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the BibDesk open source project, we wanted to have legit in-app
apple help, as well as a web page (and PDF), without maintaining
separate sources, since we were all working out of spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried a few free options, and eventually worked out something
decent with Texinfo, a latex-like markup language that can be
processed into latex (and then PDF) or HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a custom init file to have the (standard) texi2html script
print out apple help compatible HTML. One post-processing script and a
simple xcode script build phase later, and we get apple help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also get a version a little more suitable for the web (more content
per page) from the same source: &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sf.net/manual/"&gt;http://bibdesk.sf.net/manual/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worked well for a couple of years, and it's a good choice if you
don't mind learning texinfo (it's pretty nice compared to
writing in Docbook or HTML, IMO), and very good for version-controlled collaboration,
since it's just text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example, here's what the help source text looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://bibdesk.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/bibdesk/trunk/bibdesk/English.lproj/BibDesk%20Help/bibdesk.texi?view=markup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The init file and other stuff is here:
http://bibdesk.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/bibdesk/trunk/bibdesk/BibDesk%20Help/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone's curious about it, feel free to ask me questions here. I'll try
to remember how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>apple-help</category><category>bibdesk</category><category>help</category><category>texinfo</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/02/how-bibdesk-generates-apple-help-and-a-web-manual/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 07:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"BibDesk, BibTeX and Subversion" from Terrell Russell</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/bibdesk-bibtex-and-subversion-from-terrell-russell/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A nice writeup of using BibDesk with Subversion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://weblog.terrellrussell.com/2007/02/bibdesk-bibtex-and-subversion-an-academics-necessity/"&gt;BibDesk, BibTeX and Subversion - An academic's necessity&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided I'd choose based on 1) open formats, 2) documentation, and an 3) open development model (open source). After looking through RefWorks, vanilla BibTeX files, ProCite, EndNote, Reference Manager (the application) and BibDesk, I chose BibDesk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/bibdesk-bibtex-and-subversion-from-terrell-russell/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 04:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Share how you use BibDesk</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/share-how-you-use-bibdesk/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/"&gt;BibDesk&lt;/a&gt;, I want to hear how you use it - what features you use most, and how you have it set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've added a page to the BibDesk wiki to share &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/User_Screenshots"&gt;User Screenshots&lt;/a&gt; - add a section there about what you do with BibDesk, and share your experiences. I added my own thoughts already, to get things started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note, image uploading on the wiki is broken right now, I'll fix it as soon as I can and update this post. Please add text anyway!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><category>me</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/share-how-you-use-bibdesk/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 20:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BibDesk and the hCite Microformat</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/bibdesk-and-the-hcite-microformat/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is about building an iTunes store-style interface to the web's bibliographic information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been pushing along the &lt;a href="http://microformats.org/wiki/citation"&gt;hCite &lt;/a&gt; Microformat process, which will set a standard for HTML publishers to add simple semantic markup to their pages that programs like BibDesk can read as citation metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In stark contrast to great but complex things like Z39.50, if you can publish a web page, you can serve citation metadata. No need to have servers to support complicated queries, let google do the hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progress on the standard has been slow, and so far there is only one beta implementation to help focus the talks - Brian Suda's &lt;a href="http://suda.co.uk/projects/microformats/X2C/"&gt;X2C&lt;/a&gt; XSL stylesheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of building momentum, I've added support for parsing hCite to a private build of BibDesk. For now, we're just discussing how to merge it, but soon the feature will show up in nightly builds, and anyone can start testing and getting experience with the emerging standard. I'll update when it's available, but until then, here's a rough screenshot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/bdwebgroupscreenshot.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; this feature is now in the latest &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.demokratia.org/beta/"&gt;nightly builds&lt;/a&gt;, but it's hidden because hCite isn't final. To see the web group, type &lt;code&gt;defaults write edu.ucsd.cs.mmccrack.bibdesk BDSKShouldShowWebGroup true&lt;/code&gt; (all one line) at the command line before running a recent nightly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><category>bibliography</category><category>hcite</category><category>metadata</category><category>microformats</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/bibdesk-and-the-hcite-microformat/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2007 15:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BibDesk OpenURL script workflow</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/bibdesk-openurl-script-workflow/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love reading about how people use BibDesk. Over on the &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum_id=11760"&gt;bibdesk-users mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, James Howison &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum_id=11760"&gt;explains in detail&lt;/a&gt; how Alex Montgomery's OpenURL script is making him happy. The short version: "Zero typing of the bibliographic details :)"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he explains, you can find some great scripts for BibDesk on the wiki at &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/BibDesk_Applescripts"&gt;BibDesk Applescripts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><category>mac</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/bibdesk-openurl-script-workflow/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 12:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BibDesk 1.3 Highlights</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/bibdesk-1-3/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;BibDesk 1.3 was just released (see &lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?thread_id=31405038&amp;amp;forum;_id=11760"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for very complete release notes), and this release adds a few features that were requested four &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; ago - searching &lt;a href="http://www.pubmed.org"&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; and libraries with Z39.50 support. If you use those resources, this means no more downloading files to import references - just search from within BibDesk, and your results show up as a group that you can browse and through with the same interface you use for your local references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other notable features include using URLs or scripts as sources for external groups - if you have a script that can generate data BibDesk can read, its output can show up as a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two new data formats are now supported for importing - MARC (and some MARC XML) and Refer. Dublin Core XML is also supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this is also the first version that will no longer launch on Mac OS X 10.3.9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to everyone involved - check out the &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/Contributors"&gt;contributors wiki page&lt;/a&gt; for who to thank!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><category>computers</category><category>mac</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/bibdesk-1-3/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 12:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>AutoFill: BibDesk and DC-HTML</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/08/autofill-bibdesk-and-dc-html/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my first contribution to &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sf.net"&gt;BibDesk&lt;/a&gt; in a while, I've added the ability to read Dublin Core metadata when it is encoded in HTML META tags on a web page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means is that when using the "New Publications from Web" feature, some sites you browse to will have the publication's information filled in for you, so you don't have to type anything at all. The &lt;a href="http://www.eprints.org/"&gt;Eprints.org&lt;/a&gt; open archive software does this, so check out their &lt;a href="http://www.eprints.org/software/archives/"&gt;list of archives&lt;/a&gt; for examples to test it out on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'll be in the next version, which isn't scheduled yet, so if you'd like to try it out sooner, see the &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.demokratia.org/beta/"&gt;nightly builds&lt;/a&gt; page and heed its warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you publish web sites with one-page-per-pubcation and want info about embedding DC terms in your meta tags, see the &lt;a href="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcq-html/"&gt;Dublin Core recommendation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to support AutoFill for a site that doesn't have one page per publication, or would like to provide more metadata, I suggest waiting for the &lt;a href="http://microformats.org/wiki/citation"&gt;citation microformat&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to ask why...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: I made a 12-second movie of how it works - &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/BibDesk-DCHTML-screencast.mov"&gt;BibDesk, EPrints and Dublin Core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><category>bibliography</category><category>mac</category><category>metadata</category><category>programming</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/08/autofill-bibdesk-and-dc-html/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>