<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (cocoa)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 10:00:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for July 19th through July 22nd</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/07/links-for-july-19th-through-july-22nd.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for July 19th through July 22nd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nerdsonwallstreet.com/artificial-intelligence-and-wall-street-trading-309/"&gt;Artificial Intelligence Applications | Securities Trading | Nerds on Wall Street | Computational Finance&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ihnatko.com/2011/07/22/making-desktop-webapps-in-lion/"&gt;Making Desktop Webapps in Lion - Andy Ihnatko's Celestial Waste of Bandwidth (BETA)&lt;/a&gt; - Site-specific browsing gets OS support. Just in time for the inspiration for my webmail.app (GMail) to get permanently tagged with a social network's notification wart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://objectivistc.tumblr.com/post/7872364181/tagged-pointers-and-fast-pathed-cfnumber-integers-in"&gt;Objectivist-C - Tagged pointers and fast-pathed CFNumber integers in Lion&lt;/a&gt; - Neat little trick to reduce the impact of boxing/unboxing. I haven't written cocoa code in a long time, so I'm not really clear on how often this would apply. I thought there were a lot of places where the API just uses raw ints already?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://putthison.com/post/6286554010/we-got-it-for-free-randolph-engineering-ive"&gt;Put This On • We Got It for Free: Randolph Engineering I've...&lt;/a&gt; - I need new sunglasses, and I'm too old for plastic surfer shades. Wear those to a business lunch and you look like a chump. But aviators can make you look like some kind of fratbro, so what to do? I turn to Put This On.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dashes.com/anil/2011/07/if-your-websites-full-of-assholes-its-your-fault.html"&gt;If your website's full of assholes, it's your fault - Anil Dash&lt;/a&gt; - A great post about applying what we've learned over human history to make communities work, to the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, the web is just people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/bibuxton/buxtoncollection/"&gt;Buxton collection&lt;/a&gt; - a gallery of technology design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>Buxton</category><category>cocoa</category><category>community</category><category>culture</category><category>interaction</category><category>links</category><category>lion</category><category>macosx</category><category>museum</category><category>optimization</category><category>people</category><category>performance</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>ssb</category><category>sunglasses</category><category>tagged-pointer</category><category>web</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/07/links-for-july-19th-through-july-22nd.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 20:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TextShapeView</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/09/textshapeview.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;TextShapeView was another Cocoa Text system hack project I started a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a view that displays a zoomed out view of a string from a text view, with indentation, along with a rectangle showing where the text view is in the file. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can click around in the view to move the  It also highlights the selection, and draws lines in blue if they contain the string in the NSFindPBoard, so you can see &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the lines in the file that match when you use the Find panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is available under a Creative Commons license, and I'd ask that if you make any improvements, you send them back to me or join the 'leverage' sourceforge project, where the code is hosted. I wanted to eventually make this into a Cocoa text plugin like &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/09/an-update-on-the-incremental-search-plug/"&gt;my I-Search plugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;a href="http://leverage.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/textshape/trunk/"&gt;SVN repository for the textshape code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/TextShapeView.tgz"&gt;Source code Tarball&lt;/a&gt; with a demo app, shown in the screenshot below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/tsvPic.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/tsvPic.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>NSTextView</category><category>cocoa</category><category>mac</category><category>text</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/09/textshapeview.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 19:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>iCal's Text Field Jumble</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/11/text-field-jumble.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've written here before about text fields, particularly the problem of having a good-looking 'display' mode and a separate 'edit' mode for data you don't edit so often, like in AddressBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent version of iCal decided that events are write-once-read-many as well. You now have to use cmd-E to get into edit mode, while cmd-I just gives you a small display mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm mostly OK with that, although I find I edit events about as often as I look at their info windows - after editing I usually just deal with alarms, not the events themselves. The casual glance at the time and title is always enough - I think either you're looking at the time and title or you're editing. I don't see the appeal in the new 'info-only' mode (if it's actually new - it seems new.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the change does highlight the jumble of editable text fields and text-like fields in the edit window:
&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp2/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/pastedgraphic-1.tiff"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp2/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/pastedgraphic-1.tiff"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp2/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/pastedgraphic.tiff"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp2/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/pastedgraphic.tiff"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "Add Attendees" link and the "None" placeholder for url act the same - you click on them, and enter text.
One's a link and one's mute gray text. Why?
For my part, I think the gray text is too understated, and the link is too garish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other differences: you can tab to the "url" field, but you can't tab to "attendees"... until you add one, then you can. Once you click on either of them, the url field pops up a plain white raised NSTextField, but the attendees field is sunken and translucent, apparently an NSTokenField?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of the blue links could also be buttons. I'm still not completely sold on replacing buttons with links, but I can understand the trend. I think a small plus-sign button would be fine for "Add File", though, and "Attendees" ought to be a text field. Why force the user to use the mouse when adding data to an event?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I think the "Add Attendees" link/field is pretty strange. I'm curious if I missing a precedent somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cocoa</category><category>mac</category><category>programming</category><category>ui</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/11/text-field-jumble.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 22:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>