<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (computing)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 08:29:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links: screen for X, computer history, Linux</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/02/links-screen-for-x-computer-history-linux/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for February 21st through February 22nd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://xpra.org/"&gt;http://xpra.org/ (Wayland - Beyond X (The H) [LWN.net])&lt;/a&gt; - a 'screen' for X exists. A SCREEN FOR X EXISTS!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://rogerbraun.net/a-client-side-bayes-classifier-for-hacker-new"&gt;A client-side Bayes classifier for Hacker News - Japomatik&lt;/a&gt; - Very cool idea. I'd like to see if I can bend it to my purposes - flag all comments by people under, say, 28 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://conservancy.umn.edu/handle/59493"&gt;University of Minnesota Digital Conservancy: Oral history interviews&lt;/a&gt; - "CBI holds one of the world's largest collections of research-grade oral history interviews relating to the history of computers, software, and networking. Most of the 300-plus oral histories have been developed in conjunction with grant-funded research projects on topics such as the development of the software industry, the influence of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), and the early history of computer science departments."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dgp.toronto.edu/people/stam/reality/Research/pdf/GDC03.pdf"&gt;Real-Time Fluid Dynamics for Games&lt;/a&gt; - from Jos Stam at Alias | Wavefront, at GDC 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3594236"&gt;This article is not well-informed. I worked on or sat next to people who worked ... | Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; - Linux history. didn't bother to read orig. article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.canonical.com/2012/02/the-unity-design-process-and-how-you-can-play-a-part-in-it/"&gt;The Unity design process (and how you can play a part in it)&lt;/a&gt; - to read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/17727827043"&gt;(via Photo | Mike Industries)&lt;/a&gt; - basketball face&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>X</category><category>basketball</category><category>bayes</category><category>classifier</category><category>computing</category><category>dbus</category><category>design</category><category>fluid-dynamics</category><category>games</category><category>history</category><category>hn</category><category>interviews</category><category>javascript</category><category>links</category><category>linux</category><category>physics</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>programming</category><category>screen</category><category>simulation</category><category>ubuntu</category><category>visualization</category><category>x11</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/02/links-screen-for-x-computer-history-linux/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Link: The Future of Computing Performance: Game Over or Next Level?</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/06/link-the-future-of-computing-performance-game-over-or-next-level/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;From the National Academies: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nap.edu/catalog.php?record_id=12980"&gt;The Future of Computing Performance: Game Over or Next Level?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice, thorough explanation of the current challenges in computing performance, ranging from transistor-level power vs. speed problems, up to how to program the circuits we're likely to end up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also includes a bonus reprint of two classic papers, Gordon Moore's "Cramming More Components onto Integrated Circuits" from 1965 - that's the paper you might expect it is, and Robert Dennard's "Design of Ion-Implanted MOSFET’s with Very Small Physical Dimensions", which I was less familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>computing</category><category>performance</category><category>power</category><category>research</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/06/link-the-future-of-computing-performance-game-over-or-next-level/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 18:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tinkering</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/09/tinkering/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I really liked a recent post by Alex Payne titled &lt;a href="http://al3x.net/2009/08/10/switching-season.html"&gt;Switching Season&lt;/a&gt;.  He says he gets an itch every year or so to go try something different, and I can sympathize. What he says at the end really resonates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s about computer &lt;em&gt;usage&lt;/em&gt; as a creative act, something that becomes harder and harder to experience the more proficient one gets with a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel this way every once in a while too - It used to be fun just getting a computer to do something. Once you know enough about how it works and most of what you do is handled pretty smoothly, some of the fun goes out of it. The problem with high-quality free apps like Mail and Address Book is that they remove the motivation for people to tinker with new ways of using computers for the same old things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This urge to tinker is pretty strong, at least for me, and I think it might be one reason why I'm not so excited about web and mobile (at least iPhone) programming. Both platforms have a lot going for them, but the barrier to tinkering with my data is high - sometimes I can't get my data out of a service, and if I want to write scripts to combine two web apps, where do they run?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I've seen a lot of great things come from the community built around BibDesk's scripting interface, and if it were a web app, none of that would have happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>computing</category><category>desktopvswebapps</category><category>mac</category><category>scripting</category><category>tinkering</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/09/tinkering/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 19:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>