<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (database)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 10:00:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for January 23rd through January 25th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-january-23rd-through-january-25th.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for January 23rd through January 25th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.canonical.com/2012/01/introducing-the-hud-say-hello-to-the-future-of-the-menu/"&gt;Introducing the HUD. Say hello to the future of the menu. « Canonical Design&lt;/a&gt; - Canonical is moving towards no menus and just using a quicksilver-style "HUD" smart text interface. That's great - menus stink and this gives a path to voice control too, but there's a big discovery problem to be attacked (which menus also have but not as bad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://voices.canonical.com/ubuntuone/?p=1342"&gt;Ubuntu One Blog » Blog Archive » U1DB technical preview release: tell us what you think!&lt;/a&gt; - Blog post announcing u1db preview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://people.canonical.com/~aquarius/u1db-docs/"&gt;U1DB -- u1db v0.0.1.dev.0 documentation&lt;/a&gt; - Developer preview documentation. Their summary:
"
U1DB is a database API for synchronised databases of JSON documents. It's simple to use in applications, and allows apps to store documents and synchronise them between machines and devices. U1DB itself is not a database: instead, it's an API which can be backed by any database for storage. This means that you can use u1db on different platforms, from different languages, and backed on to different databases, and sync between all of them.
"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>HUD</category><category>WIMP</category><category>canonical</category><category>cloud</category><category>database</category><category>desktop</category><category>links</category><category>linux</category><category>menu</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>python</category><category>sync</category><category>u1db</category><category>ubuntu</category><category>ubuntu-one</category><category>ui</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-january-23rd-through-january-25th.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 19:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links for December 28th - 29th (Including PyCon2012 Talks of Interest)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-december-28th-29th-including-pycon2012-talks-of-interest.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for December 28th through December 29th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mail.python.org/pipermail/email-sig/"&gt;The Email-SIG Archives&lt;/a&gt; - Archives of group working on email package in python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.abisource.com/projects/link-grammar/"&gt;Link Grammar&lt;/a&gt; - grammar parsing package homepage as part of abiword&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://networkx.lanl.gov/"&gt;Overview -- NetworkX 1.6 documentation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dmalcolm.livejournal.com/6560.html"&gt;dmalcolm - Automatically detecting reference-count bugs in Python extension modules&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/468/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: Parsing Horrible Things&lt;/a&gt; - If you've ever wanted to get started with parsers, here's your chance for a ground-floor introduction. A harebrained spare-time project gives birth to a whirlwind journey from basic algorithms to Python libraries and, at last, to a parser for one of the craziest syntaxes out there: the MediaWiki grammar that drives Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/426/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: Python for data lovers&lt;/a&gt; - Exploring and analyzing data can be daunting and time-consuming, even for data lovers. Python can make the process fun and exciting. We will present techniques of data analysis, along with python tools that help you explore and map data. Our talk includes examples that show how python libraries such as csvkit, matplotlib, scipy, networkx and pysal can help you dig into and make sense of your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/407/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: Time series analysis in python&lt;/a&gt; - Analyzing, storing and visualizing time-series efficiently are recurring though difficult tasks in various aspects of scientific data analysis such as meteorological forecasting, financial modeling, ... In this talk we will explore the current Python ecosystem for doing this effectively, comparing options, using only open source packages that are mature yet still under active development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/378/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: Email package&lt;/a&gt; - The email package in the Python Standard library has had a somewhat rocky transition into the Python3 era, and still doesn't handle non-ASCII easily. That is about to change. This talk will compare how things worked in Python2 (the past), how things work now (in Python3.2), and how things will work much better in the future (hopefully Python3.3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/341/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: Advanced SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt; - How do you take the big step from casual SQLAlchemy user, who treats your database as a mysterious object store, to advanced power user, who optimizes critical queries, plans indexing and migrations, and generates efficient reports? This talk will teach you how databases think; why humanity invented the Relational Algebra; and how SQLAlchemy grants you access to relational power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/304/"&gt;PyCon US 2012 : Python FUSE&lt;/a&gt; - Contrary to classical kernel residing file-systems in *NIX, FUSE is an API to develop file systems in user space. This talk details internals of FUSE, developing your own file-system with Python-FUSE, followed by creative application of Python-FUSE based file system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/303/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: What's new in the PyStdLib&lt;/a&gt; - Lots of Interesting stuff has gone into Python Standard library in 2.7, 3.1, 3.2 and 3.3 release. Some interesting features that went in really make programmers life easy and it can bring in a 'wow' factor to their code. Additionally, it can also help the external library developers to relook at the their libraries to use new facilities available from standard library modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk distills stuff from What's new document from 2.7, 3.2 and 3.3 and presents some of the choicest new features from Python standard library. Since a lots has gone in since 2.7, focus would be given to those which have had good discussion in tracker or in python-dev and would in general was a most sought out one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/246/"&gt;PyCon US 2012: Code Generation in Python: Dismantling Jinja&lt;/a&gt; - For many DSLs such as templating languages it's important to use code generation to achieve acceptable performance in Python. The current version of Jinja went through many different iterations to end up where it is currently. This talk walks through the design of Jinja2's compiler infrastructure and why it works the way it works and how one can use newer Python features for better results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/196/"&gt;Mailman 3 -- PyCon US 2012&lt;/a&gt; - Mailman 3 has been in development for several years. This is an evolution of the ever popular mailing list management system that runs thousands of mailing lists around the world. This talk describes how the code has been modernized and how the architectural deficiencies of Mailman 2 have been addressed using REST and other technologies. This is a spinoff from the AOSA chapter on Mailman 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.opencog.org/w/RelEx"&gt;RelEx Dependency Relationship Extractor - OpenCog&lt;/a&gt; - RelEx, a narrow-AI component of OpenCog, is an English-language semantic dependency relationship extractor, built on the Carnegie-Mellon Link Grammar parser. It uses a series of graph rewriting rules to identify subject, object, indirect object and many other syntactic dependency relationships between words in a sentence. That is, it generates the dependency trees of a dependency grammar. Its set of dependency relations it employs resemble those of Dekang Lin's MiniPar and the Stanford parser (and it has an explicit compatibility mode). It is inspired in part by the ideas of Hudson's Word Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://notes.pinboard.in/u%3Ammc/236478884c5e2422513d"&gt;Could you start a blog on this thing?&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vr-zone.com/articles/chinese-high-end-cpus-are-now-in-the-game--details--part-2-alpha/14347.html"&gt;Chinese high end CPUs are now in the game - details: Part 2, Alpha by VR-Zone.com&lt;/a&gt; - Chinese supercomputer uses Alpha architecture. Article has some interesting details and some cringeworthy breathless praise for the lamented Alpha chips…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>AI</category><category>DSL</category><category>FUSE</category><category>REST</category><category>alpha</category><category>analysis</category><category>blog</category><category>china</category><category>code</category><category>code-generation</category><category>computer-architecture</category><category>data</category><category>database</category><category>email</category><category>filesystem</category><category>gcc</category><category>graph</category><category>graph-processing</category><category>jinja</category><category>linkgrammar</category><category>links</category><category>mailman</category><category>matplotlib</category><category>network</category><category>nlp</category><category>opencog</category><category>parsing</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>pycon2012</category><category>python</category><category>python3</category><category>science</category><category>sqlalchemy</category><category>static-analysis</category><category>sunway</category><category>talk</category><category>templating</category><category>text</category><category>time-series</category><category>visualization</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-december-28th-29th-including-pycon2012-talks-of-interest.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links for November 19th through November 25th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/12/links-for-november-19th-through-november-25th.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for November 19th through November 25th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/2/5749fbb8-100d-11e1-a468-00144feabdc0.html#axzz1emPiPJlK"&gt;Norway: an Eden with wifi - FT.com&lt;/a&gt; - "Visiting Norway during the global crisis felt like prosperity tourism, or "wealth porn"."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://axisofeval.blogspot.com/2011/11/extensible-way-of-thinking.html"&gt;The Axis of Eval: The extensible way of thinking&lt;/a&gt; - An interesting way of looking at requiring types: it hampers extensibility…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/u1db"&gt;U1DB in Launchpad&lt;/a&gt; - Potential replacement for desktopcouch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.oracle.com/run/entry/how_john_got_15x_improvement"&gt;How John Got 15x Improvement Without Really Trying (Compile My Code)&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>case</category><category>couchdb</category><category>database</category><category>desktop</category><category>extensibility</category><category>gift</category><category>kindle</category><category>links</category><category>lisp</category><category>mit-ai</category><category>norway</category><category>open-source</category><category>optimization</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>programming</category><category>prosperity</category><category>rms</category><category>sync</category><category>types</category><category>ubuntu</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/12/links-for-november-19th-through-november-25th.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 20:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>