<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (ipad)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/ipad.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for January 11th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-january-11th-2/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for January 11th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tromey.com/elpa/"&gt;Welcome to ELPA&lt;/a&gt; - emacs lisp package archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=2038036"&gt;OCaml for the Masses - ACM Queue&lt;/a&gt; - Why the next language you learn should be functional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by Yaron Minsky, Jane Street&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the elegant implementation is a function. Not a method. Not a class. Not a framework. Just a function. - John Carmack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.michaeleisen.org/blog/?p=807"&gt;Elsevier-funded NY Congresswoman Carolyn Maloney Wants to Deny Americans Access to Taxpayer Funded Research&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://byrdandbelle.bigcartel.com/"&gt;byrd and belle&lt;/a&gt; - Nice looking sleeves with wool felt and leather&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>accessories</category><category>case</category><category>elisp</category><category>emacs</category><category>functional</category><category>google</category><category>hn</category><category>ipad</category><category>iphone</category><category>journals</category><category>kindle</category><category>laptop</category><category>links</category><category>lisp</category><category>ocaml</category><category>open-access</category><category>package-manager</category><category>personalized-search</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>programming</category><category>publication</category><category>research</category><category>search</category><category>sleeve</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-january-11th-2/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 19:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tinkering in the Sideshow</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/02/tinkering-in-the-sideshow/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="http://al3x.net/2010/01/28/ipad.html"&gt;Alex Payne&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset"&gt;Mark Pilgrim&lt;/a&gt; both made some heartfelt arguments explaining why they think the fact that Apple's vision of the computing future as a relatively closed appliance is depressing. I agree, and I want to explain exactly why, now that I think I've figured it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each post got plenty of responses. Dissenters have a wide variety of reasons for why it's no big deal, ranging from "tomorrows tinkerers will just play with different technology, like &lt;a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset#comment-13600"&gt;bio-mecha&lt;/a&gt;" (fascinating!), to a lot of people saying, essentially, "Just don't buy the appliance if you want a computer" (obvious!). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others have made a solid point that the iPad is the next big computing paradigm. Steven Frank calls it a &lt;a href="http://stevenf.tumblr.com/post/359224392/i-need-to-talk-to-you-about-computers-ive-been"&gt;"New World"&lt;/a&gt; device. I can't help but agree, and of course powerful devices that empower instead of confuse the user are a good thing. Replacing most of the world's overcomplicated, fussy laptops with focused and reliable devices is a good thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, general purpose, hackable computers are not really going away, not soon. Even if everyone uses an iPad for personal stuff and a Chrome OS netbook to access private cloud services for business work, there will still be a need for workstations, and I hope the people building complete personal systems out of Free Software don't give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in a response to comments on his post, &lt;a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset#comment-13616"&gt;Mark Pilgrim made a gloomy prediction&lt;/a&gt;: "People haven’t figured it out yet, but Mac OS X is on its last legs. By 2015, Apple will make appliances and developer add-ons. Not general purpose computing devices." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask me, this is the real problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that hackable computers &lt;em&gt;that I want to use&lt;/em&gt; could very well be fading out. Maybe Mark's overstating things, but I would not be surprised to see the Mac, and OS X, as a relatively low priority for Apple in the near future. Design and development effort and creativity will naturally go increasingly toward the more profitable platform - the one making computing finally pleasant for the normal person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm worried that this will happen for third-party developers too. &lt;a href="http://violasong.com/2010/02/my-worst-ipad-fears"&gt;I'm not the only one.&lt;/a&gt; Back in 2002, Brent Simmons described developing user code for the Mac as &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/2002/09/19/why_i_develop_for_mac_os_x"&gt;"the show"&lt;/a&gt;. Is there any doubt that Apple's mobile OS is "the show" now? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does that leave the rest of us who still have to or want to use a more powerful platform? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>ipad</category><category>me</category><category>melancholy</category><category>tinkering</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/02/tinkering-in-the-sideshow/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 10:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>