<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (lists)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 10:00:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Filters: Thunderbird 3</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/filters-thunderbird-3.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;How well does Thunderbird 3 let me create filters to handle heavy traffic lists?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's not much support for using a message to build a filter from, which I think is the most natural workflow. The menu item "Tools &amp;gt; Message Filters…" opens a dialog box that could use some simplification. For example, the buttons to move filters up and down in order are unnecessary - you should be able to just drag the filters around in the table. There are plenty of other non-mac-like UI elements here. Another example of overcomplicated UI is the "Filter Log" button. At best this is an "advanced" preference, but it's a big button at the top - and it's misnamed. It opens a sheet to let you turn the logging on, but who knows how you actually view the logging?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l33l1uJlv51qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other UI problems when trying to add the filter - I didn't think ahead of time that I'd need to create the folder to send the filtered messages to. The Message Filters dialog seems modal, because the menubar goes away when it's in focus, but it's not really - so I just created the new folder back on the main window while the new-filter sheet was still open. A little strange, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also lacking a way to do a dry-run of the filter- to test which messages will match, before just letting it loose on your mailbox. This is a really important feature, especially when filters can do destructive or un-recoverable things like running a script (not in Thunderbird, but present in other mailers) or send a response.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>filters</category><category>lists</category><category>thunderbird-3</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/filters-thunderbird-3.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dealing with High-traffic Lists and Filters</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/dealing-with-high-traffic-lists-and-filters.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that can make a big difference in a client is how well it helps you cope with heavy-traffic lists. Sometimes we need to stay on top of a firehose, and a client that helps filter out the noise and lets you keep track of what's going on in sometimes very long threads is an invaluable tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll find plenty of opinions about how to do this, but I think it's well established that daily digests are not a great way to deal with traffic. It's great to only check things occasionally, but most list software doesn't let you say when it'll dump the huge pile into your inbox, and most mail software doesn't handle the multipart/digest format very well - usually it just gets combined into one big message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the best way is first to filter the list messages out of the inbox, and only check in on it every so often (more often if it's an important list for your job). You want to be able to quickly skim what's new since you last checked in - new threads, what changed in threads you've looked at already, etc. One way to do this is to have another filter to flag messages that are "interesting" in some way - either to me or mentioning me or my topics of interest, or from interesting people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to spread out comments on each client into a few posts over the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>filters</category><category>lists</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/dealing-with-high-traffic-lists-and-filters.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 17:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversation View &amp; Keeping up with Lists</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/conversation-view-keeping-up-with-lists.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Here's a set of screenshots that show how conversation view can help keeping up with a public list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been subscribed to the LLVM-dev mailing list for years in GMail, and for about a week in my mikechecksmail test account. I'm not active in the LLVM project - it's just something I want to check in on occasionally. (For a while I had a filter that popped up any mention of Fortran). So when I check in, I want to skim the threads and read anything that's interesting. Usually that means I'm finding a thread that's already pretty long and I'm reading the whole thread from the beginning the first time I see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm interested to hear if that's not how you read public high-traffic lists - do you try to keep up with all the threads as they come in? I did that for a while, but it's hard to keep up with and probably isn't actually your job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with that workflow in mind, how do our clients fare?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GMail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GMail, when you click on a new thread (aka "conversation") you get the messages all on one page, starting with the earliest - perfect for reading from the beginning. This shot shows the first couple of messages in a medium size thread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ai4mO4Al1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty good about handling quotes, too. If you're reading through an entire thread at a time, it's nice to have quoted text collapsed so you don't end up scrolling past the same paragraphs over and over. Of course, quoted text can be critical for understanding the new text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;quoted&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;quoted&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;!!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But in my judgement, barring some natural language analysis, the best default is to collapse and let the user click to expand quotes when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you return to a thread and it has new messages, it'll collapse the ones you've seen before, handy to get a quick update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ajpwBp531qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you select "Show Conversations" in the "View" menu, Postbox shows something like a conversation-view when you select an entire thread. If you don't have that option on, or you select more than one message in any other way - like shift-or-command-clicking multiple messages, you get a blank content view. Not very useful, but a minor point - after all, GMail doesn't really show the list in the same page as the content anyway, so they've avoided that design problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major problem with Postbox's conversation view - for this list-catchup task - is that it sorts the messages with the newest ones at the top. This is exactly the wrong thing for reading a whole thread, and I couldn't find a way to change this sort order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what it looks like on that same thread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ajxnHkKi1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple other minor nitpicks - the info pane with the sender and links on the right-hand side only shows its info for the most recent message - if you want that info for another message, you have to select just that message in the list view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you revisit the thread, it marks every message as read, and there's no way to see what's new:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ajzroxSb1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still looking at the thread when new messages in that thread come in, it'll give you a nice alert and lets you refresh the view, but then the problem is still there - it's up to you to see what's new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird 3 has a summary view, but it's not thread-centric.
It just shows the sender, date and first few lines (smashed together without newlines) of each message you've selected. If you select a thread, it's kind of like a conversation view, but if you select multiple unrelated messages, it'll just show the messages in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ak9yEo0u1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly there's some room for improvement there. I won't pick on it too much, except to say that smashing the text together for a summary makes this view basically useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Mail doesn't really try to give you a summary of a thread or a conversation view - it'll show which mails are new, but then you have to click through to an individual view of each message. Here's what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1akg4XWv41qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't sloppy like Thunderbird's view, but it's not very useful either. For this and other reasons, keeping up with public mailing lists in Apple Mail is pretty painful. That's why I moved most of my list subscriptions over to GMail a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>conversation-view</category><category>gmail</category><category>lists</category><category>postbox</category><category>thunderbird</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/conversation-view-keeping-up-with-lists.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 19:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Public List Tests: The Firehose</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/public-list-tests-the-firehose.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm signing up for a couple of public mailing lists to test how the clients help me handle the firehose of potentially-relevant emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years now, I've used GMail exclusively for public lists, because the conversation view maps really well to how I like to scan most lists - I like to see what new threads have started, and only read individual messages if the topic is interesting. I also tend to look at a thread if someone smart has weighed in, so if a client helps me pick that out, it's good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GMail, it only shows three or so of the people in any thread, so I have resorted to filters that star any thread where smart people are talking. I don't love that solution, though, since I also use stars to manually flag something as important, and I'd rather not mix things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've signed up for one low-traffic list (&lt;a href="https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/pyobjc-dev"&gt;PyObjC-dev&lt;/a&gt;) and one higher-traffic list (&lt;a href="http://lists.cs.uiuc.edu/mailman/listinfo/llvmdev"&gt;LLVM-dev&lt;/a&gt;), since different traffic levels are different problems. A really high-traffic list can really test a client's filtering and thread display design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these lists are &lt;a href="http://list.org/"&gt;Mailman&lt;/a&gt; lists, which is a very broadly used system and it's what I'm used to. I'm open to hearing about other kinds of lists with different features that might change things, though - leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now I'm starting with digests off, which I like because I prefer to see things by thread instead of by date. Some clients do unpack digests automatically, so I might test that out sometime, but I think that a client should just control when it shows you bulk mail instead of just asking the list to only send it once a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll report here as the traffic builds and we'll see how each client handles it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>conversation-view</category><category>gmail</category><category>lists</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/public-list-tests-the-firehose.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 17:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>