<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (localization)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/localization.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for February 7th through February 9th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/02/links-for-february-7th-through-february-9th/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for February 7th through February 9th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.github.com/effectivescala/"&gt;Effective Scala&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://courses.csail.mit.edu/6.851/spring12/lectures"&gt;Video lectures for 6.851, advanced data structures&lt;/a&gt; - Prof. Erik Demaine's 6.851 lectures recorded with synchronized lecture notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tobami/codespeed/"&gt;tobami/codespeed - GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - Python and django performance monitoring tool. Used for speed.pypy.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tratt.net/laurie/research/publications/html/tratt__experiences_with_an_icon_like_expression_evaluation_system/"&gt;Experiences with an Icon-like Expression Evaluation System&lt;/a&gt; - Interesting and accessible trip through Icon's expression semantics and Converge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/amoffat/pbs"&gt;amoffat/pbs - GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - Clever library to let you start subprograms from python as if they were python functions. Much more usable than the stuff I'm used to in the pystdlib...
Almost as concise as backticks and looks more flexible too (ie, handles piping)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tratt.net/laurie/tech_articles/articles/fast_enough_vms_in_fast_enough_time"&gt;Laurence Tratt: Fast Enough VMs in Fast Enough Time&lt;/a&gt; - "If you can stomach the smell, put yourself briefly in the shoes of a programming language designer. What you want to do is create new programming languages, combining new and old ideas into a fresh whole. It sounds like a fun, intellectually demanding job, and occasionally it is. However, we know from experience that languages that exist solely in the mind or on paper are mostly worthless: it is only when they are implemented and we can try them out that we can evaluate them. As well as a language design, therefore, we need a corresponding language implementation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mobiata.com/blog/2012/02/08/twine-string-management-ios-mac-os-x"&gt;Introducing Twine: String Management for iOS, Mac OS X, and Android Development - Mobiata Blog&lt;/a&gt; - In this post I hope to show you just how bad the standard localization process is for iOS and Mac OS X apps, and how we have found a way to make it much easier for developers to localize their apps and then maintain these localizations and translations over time. In addition, I'll show you how you can easily share your translations across multiple apps and platforms. This will save your company money that would otherwise be spent duplicating your translation efforts, especially if you are developing for both iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://live.gnome.org/Conduit"&gt;Conduit - GNOME Live!&lt;/a&gt; - Conduit is a synchronization application for GNOME. It allows you to synchronize your files, photos, emails, contacts, notes, calendar data and any other type of personal information and synchronize that data with another computer, an online service, or even another electronic device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conduit manages the synchronization and conversion of data into other formats. For example, Conduit allows you to :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronize your Tomboy notes with another computer
Synchronize your your PIM data to your mobile phone, iPod, Nokia Internet tablet, or between computers
Upload photos to Flickr, Picasa, SmugMug, ShutterFly and your iPod
Any combination you can imagine, Conduit will take care of the conversion and synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://text-processing.com/demo/sentiment/"&gt;Python NLTK Sentiment Analysis with Text Classification Demo&lt;/a&gt; - neat demo but the results aren't intuitive. maybe the training set isn't great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stephenholiday.com/articles/2011/gender-prediction-with-python/"&gt;Gender Prediction with Python : Stephen Holiday&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>best-practices</category><category>classification</category><category>compiler</category><category>data-structures</category><category>demo</category><category>generators</category><category>gnome</category><category>icon</category><category>ios</category><category>languages</category><category>lectures</category><category>links</category><category>linux</category><category>localization</category><category>mit</category><category>monitoring</category><category>nltk</category><category>osx</category><category>performance</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>pl</category><category>programming</category><category>python</category><category>scala</category><category>scripting</category><category>sentiment</category><category>shell</category><category>sync</category><category>text-classification</category><category>tool</category><category>video-lectures</category><category>vm</category><category>web</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/02/links-for-february-7th-through-february-9th/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2012 22:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>