<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (me)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 09:12:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Tinkering in the Sideshow</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2010/02/tinkering-in-the-sideshow.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="http://al3x.net/2010/01/28/ipad.html"&gt;Alex Payne&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset"&gt;Mark Pilgrim&lt;/a&gt; both made some heartfelt arguments explaining why they think the fact that Apple's vision of the computing future as a relatively closed appliance is depressing. I agree, and I want to explain exactly why, now that I think I've figured it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each post got plenty of responses. Dissenters have a wide variety of reasons for why it's no big deal, ranging from "tomorrows tinkerers will just play with different technology, like &lt;a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset#comment-13600"&gt;bio-mecha&lt;/a&gt;" (fascinating!), to a lot of people saying, essentially, "Just don't buy the appliance if you want a computer" (obvious!). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others have made a solid point that the iPad is the next big computing paradigm. Steven Frank calls it a &lt;a href="http://stevenf.tumblr.com/post/359224392/i-need-to-talk-to-you-about-computers-ive-been"&gt;"New World"&lt;/a&gt; device. I can't help but agree, and of course powerful devices that empower instead of confuse the user are a good thing. Replacing most of the world's overcomplicated, fussy laptops with focused and reliable devices is a good thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, general purpose, hackable computers are not really going away, not soon. Even if everyone uses an iPad for personal stuff and a Chrome OS netbook to access private cloud services for business work, there will still be a need for workstations, and I hope the people building complete personal systems out of Free Software don't give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in a response to comments on his post, &lt;a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset#comment-13616"&gt;Mark Pilgrim made a gloomy prediction&lt;/a&gt;: "People haven’t figured it out yet, but Mac OS X is on its last legs. By 2015, Apple will make appliances and developer add-ons. Not general purpose computing devices." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask me, this is the real problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that hackable computers &lt;em&gt;that I want to use&lt;/em&gt; could very well be fading out. Maybe Mark's overstating things, but I would not be surprised to see the Mac, and OS X, as a relatively low priority for Apple in the near future. Design and development effort and creativity will naturally go increasingly toward the more profitable platform - the one making computing finally pleasant for the normal person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm worried that this will happen for third-party developers too. &lt;a href="http://violasong.com/2010/02/my-worst-ipad-fears"&gt;I'm not the only one.&lt;/a&gt; Back in 2002, Brent Simmons described developing user code for the Mac as &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/2002/09/19/why_i_develop_for_mac_os_x"&gt;"the show"&lt;/a&gt;. Is there any doubt that Apple's mobile OS is "the show" now? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where does that leave the rest of us who still have to or want to use a more powerful platform? &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>ipad</category><category>me</category><category>melancholy</category><category>tinkering</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2010/02/tinkering-in-the-sideshow.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 10:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Share how you use BibDesk</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2007/02/share-how-you-use-bibdesk.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;If you use &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/"&gt;BibDesk&lt;/a&gt;, I want to hear how you use it - what features you use most, and how you have it set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've added a page to the BibDesk wiki to share &lt;a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/User_Screenshots"&gt;User Screenshots&lt;/a&gt; - add a section there about what you do with BibDesk, and share your experiences. I added my own thoughts already, to get things started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note, image uploading on the wiki is broken right now, I'll fix it as soon as I can and update this post. Please add text anyway!)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>bibdesk</category><category>me</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2007/02/share-how-you-use-bibdesk.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 20:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leopard Tech Talk, Jan 19: LA</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2007/01/leopard-tech-talk-jan-19-la.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn't make it to WWDC last year, I'm not at Macworld this week, but I will be making it up to LA on the 19th for the &lt;a href="http://developer.apple.com/events/techtalks/northamerica.html"&gt;Leopard Tech Talk&lt;/a&gt;, to catch up. I'll probably be there the day before, owing to traffic and an inability to wake up early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any area mac devs are meeting up around then, drop me a note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if we'll know anything by then about developing for the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mac</category><category>me</category><category>programming</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2007/01/leopard-tech-talk-jan-19-la.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 23:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GTD Habits</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/11/gtd-habits.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of being aware of &lt;a href="http://davidco.com/"&gt;David Allen's&lt;/a&gt; GTD system through &lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/topics/gtd"&gt;43 Folders&lt;/a&gt; and other sites, I took the dive about a month ago and dumped all my various to-do lists and project ideas into &lt;a href="http://kinkless.com"&gt;Kinkless GTD&lt;/a&gt;. I had tried to keep reminders and actions in a variety of other systems, including emacs &lt;a href="http://staff.science.uva.nl/~dominik/Tools/org/"&gt;org-mode&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://voodoopad.com"&gt;VoodooPad&lt;/a&gt;, which I use extensively for notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never kept up a system for very long, and I believe the contexts were the key problem - having to look at tasks with different contexts in the same list is daunting - I end up not writing things down to avoid a frightening list, and keeping multiple lists around is difficult in every system I tried, until I tried Kinkless. Organizing by context gives a great feeling of confidence when I ignore huge lists that I just can't do right now. Knowing what you can't do makes getting the rest started much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to write a big series of posts describing my system or anything - I might have something to say about contexts later, but I would like to say that "vanilla" GTD can work for programmers, graduate students, etc - &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; major changes. Avoid the temptation to focus on your methods and just try using the simplest thing you can get away with. It'll probably work.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>me</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/11/gtd-habits.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 20:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Supercomputing 2006 BOF: "Is 99% Utilization of a Supercomputer a Good Thing?"</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/10/supercomputing-2006-bof-is-99-utilization-of-a-supercomputer-a-good-thing.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;For those few readers who are interested in High Performance Computing and might be going to this year's &lt;a href="http://sc06.supercomputing.org/"&gt;Supercomputing&lt;/a&gt; conference in Tampa, my advisor Allan Snavely and Jeremy Kepner from Lincoln Labs are putting on a BOF with an intriguing subject: &lt;a href="http://sc06.supercomputing.org/schedule/event_detail.php?evid=5193"&gt;"Is 99% Utilization of a Supercomputer a Good Thing?"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'll be on Thursday Nov. 16th at 12:15PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all really interesting questions, this has a quick, easy answer that reveals your point of view. My immediate answer is "No", because of the productivity problems the focus on high utilization causes for many HPC users, mainly through the use of a batch queue. However, when considering the interests of everyone involved (including the people who have to evaluate how money is spent on these systems), the only responsible way to answer is "it depends".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an interesting topic that never fails to generate some controversy, and from what I can tell we'll have some diverse speakers at the BOF (including myself, discussing user surveys we've conducted as part of DARPA HPCS). It should be enlightening.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>HPC</category><category>me</category><category>research</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/10/supercomputing-2006-bof-is-99-utilization-of-a-supercomputer-a-good-thing.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2006 23:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Portable gut check</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/09/portable-gut-check.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My Powerbook's disk died yesterday around 1pm. Since then I've been thinking about how to get by without it.
After taking far too long to realize it was beyond my troubleshooting ability, I took it to the UTC Apple store at 5 or so, and got an appointment for 7:45, then went for a drink. When I came back, the Apple store guy referred me to drivesavers - I'll have to see what their estimate is when they call me back. For now, I assume I'll have to pay whatever they ask - I was careful about backing up notes and papers to my iDisk and keeping important work files in repositories on other machines, but there is still a lot of stuff on that machine that I can't replace, and my full-backup scheme was just inconvenient enough (and my target disk just small enough) that my full backup is pretty stale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can keep working for now on lab computers and my old home Mac - I'm pretty impressed with how much I can just transfer over to another mac and keep running - I can check all my mail (IMAP or GMail), read my NetNewsWire subscriptions (Newsgator Online), go through my bookmarks (iSync &amp;amp; .mac). Pretty impressive, even without any effort to stay flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's hoping I can be back on track soon - for now I'm only a Mac user at nights, and I'm going to miss a few things during the days, to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>mac</category><category>me</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/09/portable-gut-check.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 11:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TextStructure screencast</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/08/textstructure-screencast.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In case you had no idea what I was talking about in the &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/?p=61"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I've put together a hasty screencast with no script, no soundtrack, and no editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/textstructure-screencast.mov"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/textstructure-screencast-snap.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the video you can see a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:00&lt;/em&gt;: I have found a way to show you the palm trees on my street without showing you the rest of my street. Lucky you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:08&lt;/em&gt;: After I press control-z (not my final choice for a keystroke), we get a nice little display of sections in your file. Right now I have it set up to show me ObjC methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:13&lt;/em&gt;: It shows you where you are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:16&lt;/em&gt;: ... and where you've been.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:18&lt;/em&gt;: you can jump around by clicking on the section header list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:30&lt;/em&gt;: you can search through the contents and it shows which sections match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:38&lt;/em&gt;: you can also choose from a list of other ways to slice your text - described by a bunch of regexps in a file you can tweak without recompiling the plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;0:49&lt;/em&gt;: I use Snapz Pro X and Quicksilver, which you know because I also tried to use iMovie HD and couldn't find the "Don't make my imported movies look like crap" option, so I just uploaded the original movie with no funny titles. Bummer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the &lt;a href="https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/leverage-discuss"&gt;leverage-discuss&lt;/a&gt; mailing list is up now, if you want to ask how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>mac</category><category>me</category><category>programming</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/08/textstructure-screencast.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2006 09:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>3 more text hack projects on leverage.sourceforge.net</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/08/3-more-text-hack-projects-on-leveragesourceforgenet.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;13 months ago, I &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/blosxom.pl/computers/mac/programming/meetLeverage.html"&gt;"launched"&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="http://leverage.sourceforge.net"&gt;leverage project&lt;/a&gt; on sourceforge, supposed to be a place to house all the various OS X / Cocoa text manipulation hacks I've done, including my I-Search for NSTextView InputManager hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't touched leverage since, but today I added three more projects to the SVN repository with varying appeal and usability. I also added a mailing list, &lt;a href="https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/leverage-discuss"&gt;leverage-discuss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in trying these out or working on one of these hacks, and want to ask a question, using that email list would be best, but you can also &lt;a href="mailto:michael_mccracken@mac.com"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; directly about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;TextShape&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my 2004 blog post about it: &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/blosxom.pl/computers/mac/programming/meetTSV.html"&gt;"Usability and Editing Code: TextShapeView"&lt;/a&gt; and here's the old home page for it, with a screenshot: &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/?TextShapeView"&gt;TextShapeView&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is unchanged, but it works fine on 10.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/textshape/trunk/"&gt;http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/textshape/trunk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;TextStructure&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, so long I can't even find it with google, I posted somewhere about a hacked version of &lt;a href="http://darkwing.uoregon.edu/~koch/texshop"&gt;TexShop&lt;/a&gt; that had an outline view in a drawer that showed the section structure of your TeX document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never got that working well enough to try adding it to TexShop, but I did realize that it's something that could be useful for other kinds of text as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big project, the TextStructure InputManager adds a key binding to NSTextView that pops up a window with an outline view that tries to represent the current text as an outline, using a scheme of regular expressions that mark some lines of text as "tags" with outline levels, depending on the text. It has a few regexps built in for LaTeX, ObjC, TODO &amp;amp; FIXME lines, and email quoting (which doesn't quite make sense).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also search the text for a regexp, and it will highlight the sections which contain a match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have a screenshot just yet, but I'll post about it more later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/textstructure/trunk/"&gt;http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/textstructure/trunk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;OEM : Open in Emacs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a new one, and a work-in-progress. It adds a key binding to open the text of the current text view in an emacs buffer, using a temporary file and &lt;code&gt;emacsclient&lt;/code&gt;. It currently has no way to get the text back into the text view from the file when you're done editing it in emacs, and doesn't delete the file. But it's at least partially nifty...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/oem/trunk/"&gt;http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/oem/trunk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;ISIM: Incremental Search in NSTextView&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not new, but it's in there too:
&lt;a href="http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/isim/trunk/"&gt;http://svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/leverage/isim/trunk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mac</category><category>me</category><category>programming</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/08/3-more-text-hack-projects-on-leveragesourceforgenet.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2006 22:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Take me to WWDC!</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/08/take-me-to-wwdc.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I can't make it in person to either WWDC or Buzz's party this year, and as a result, I'm bummed right out. But I haven't sulked, I thought of your feelings too. I came up with a way to make it seem kind of like I was there anyway. It's so crazy, it just might work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mike McCracken WWDC flashcards!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just print one or all of the following pictures, and bring them with you to WWDC. They're all cropped to a 3x5 ratio, so you can tuck them into your HPDA and flash them when appropriate, like a soccer referee - I suggest the following interpretations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use "Morning Mike" when you need a non-verbal way to tell someone that it's just too early to discuss APIs, GUIs, or what to do now that Apple makes a free version of your only product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/card0.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/card0.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use "Confused Mike (Afternoon session)" whenever someone says something that just doesn't make &lt;em&gt;sense&lt;/em&gt;. Whether it's their fault, or yours! Bonus points for use when you see a new abuse of the human interface guidelines. This card may also be appropriate just after seeing the amazing demo of Apple's free version of your only product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/card1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/card1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use "Cheers Mike" to suggest a trip to the bar, get women to pose with you, or to celebrate the continued absence of a free version of your only product. This may be the only appropriate card to sport during Buzz's can't-miss &lt;a href="http://weblog.scifihifi.com/2006/07/23/party-time-excellent/#comments"&gt;Weblogger's Party&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/card2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/card2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But remember, those are only guidelines. Be creative - my WWDC experience is in your hands!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take a picture with one of me, post it on flickr with the tag 'mikewwdc06' so I can see where I've been. Have fun at WWDC - to all of you and me!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mac</category><category>me</category><category>wwdc</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/08/take-me-to-wwdc.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 02:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Full Screen Focus</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/04/full-screen-focus.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I visit &lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com"&gt;43Folders&lt;/a&gt; only about once a week now - I couldn't deal with the cognitive dissonance implied by procrastinating by visiting a site about how to be more efficient and avoid procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really glad yesterday to see Merlin's post about &lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2006/04/17/fsm2-electric-boogaloo/"&gt;faking full screen mode&lt;/a&gt; with a trio of useful apps. I had tried &lt;a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/16640"&gt;Menushade&lt;/a&gt; before, and didn't really see the point - the menu bar doesn't bug me - but in combination with the other two that Merlin recommends, &lt;a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/15844"&gt;Spirited Away&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/15426"&gt;BackDrop&lt;/a&gt;, his scheme is a really great way to turn your computer into a tool for focus and not diversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought I wanted a faster auto-hide than the default 60 seconds, but after a bit of time with the delay set to zero and then a less disconcerting 10 seconds, I decided that it was confusing to lose context that quickly, so the default's been working well for me. Also, it makes diversions painfully obvious when your work-related windows blink away and you're sitting staring at ESPN. It immediately begs the question: "You've already wasted one minute - is this that important?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also reluctant to hide the dock, but I tried it, and now I'm never going back. I have &lt;a href="http://c-command.com/spamsieve"&gt;SpamSieve&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://growl.info"&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; to point out important emails (checking once an hour), and for the rest of the time, my numerous diversions are better off out of sight, out of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tactic I've started using is a dedicated browser app for Gmail. Just because I need to look at my mail doesn't mean I need to spend some time checking hockey scores - so I built a separate browser that only loads Gmail, and that temptation is gone. I'll probably post more about that sometime later, but for now, I need to get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mac</category><category>me</category><category>reviews</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2006/04/full-screen-focus.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 00:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>