<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (mikechecksmail)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 08:30:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links: Hacking, Music in Python, Rust &amp; unitasking</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/04/links-hacking-music-in-python-rust-unitaskimg/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for April 5th through April 6th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lemire.me/blog/archives/2011/06/06/why-i-still-program/"&gt;Why I still program&lt;/a&gt; - "I believe that the rejection of programming as a lower activity can be explained by the Theory of the leisure class. In effect, we do not seek utility but prestige. There is no prestige in tool-making, cooking or farming. To maximize your prestige, you must rise up to the leisure class: you work must not be immediately useful."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lemire.me/blog/archives/2012/03/20/from-counting-citations-to-measuring-usage-help-needed/"&gt;From counting citations to measuring usage (help needed!)&lt;/a&gt; - Building a Better Citation Index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mailplaneapp.com/blog/entry/workhacks.com_top_3_gmail_management_apps_for_mac"&gt;workhacks.com: Top 3 Gmail Management Apps for Mac - Mailplane Blog&lt;/a&gt; - includes a list of gmail plugins that look useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://prezjordan.github.com/Melopy/"&gt;Melopy&lt;/a&gt; - 
&lt;code&gt;  &lt;br&gt;
    """
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from melopy import Melopy
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m = Melopy('mysong')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.add_quarter_note('A4')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.add_quarter_note('C#5')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.add_quarter_note('E5')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.render()
    [==================================================] 100%
    Done
    """
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://doc.rust-lang.org/doc/tutorial.html#expression-syntax"&gt;Rust Language Tutorial: Expression Syntax&lt;/a&gt; - Starts out good, but the "leave out a semicolon to return a value" leaves a bad taste. Why overload semicolons like that? Why not just use 'ret'?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.deliberatism.com/blog/forget-self-improvement/"&gt;Forget Self-Improvement&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/schwartz/2012/03/the-magic-of-doing-one-thing-a.html"&gt;The Magic of Doing One Thing at a Time - Tony Schwartz - Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt; - A few good points on avoiding multitasking burnout. Nothing too new, but maybe if people keep repeating it in places like HBR, then it'll start to become conventional business wisdom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>business</category><category>citation</category><category>email</category><category>gmail</category><category>impact</category><category>libraries</category><category>links</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>multitasking</category><category>music</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>productivity</category><category>programming</category><category>publication</category><category>python</category><category>ranking</category><category>research</category><category>rust</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/04/links-hacking-music-in-python-rust-unitaskimg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 23:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links for June 29th through June 30th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/07/links-for-june-29th-through-june-30th/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for June 29th through June 30th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/2007/07/simple_inbox_sweeper"&gt;Daring Fireball: Simple Inbox Archiving Script for Apple Mail&lt;/a&gt; - From 2007, John Gruber's archiving applescript keeps his inbox clear of read, nonflagged items. (Apparently broken in Lion.)
Sounds like this is manually invoked though. (update: &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/gruber/status/86484584778313728"&gt;it is.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wordyard.com/2011/06/20/time-to-bake-smart-correction-tools-into-news-platforms/"&gt;Time to bake smart correction tools into news platforms — Scott Rosenberg's Wordyard&lt;/a&gt; - Scott Rosenberg on how news CMSs need to include public-viewable change-tracking. One of those things that seems obvious for a programmer…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>applescript</category><category>change-tracking</category><category>cms</category><category>email</category><category>journalism</category><category>links</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>pinboard-links</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/07/links-for-june-29th-through-june-30th/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 16:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The redesigned message view in Postbox 2.5</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/05/more-postbox-2-5-teases/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The Postbox team posted another tease for their upcoming redesign in version 2.5, this time the &lt;a href="http://www3.postbox-inc.com/?/blog/entry/postbox_2_5_-_message_view_redesign/"&gt;new message view&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to re-post all of these, but I thought this one was worth pointing out because it shows some of the thinking behind the changes - and hints at an interesting design principle: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detail views that don't change visual structure when the item they're displaying changes feel faster and more solid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you agree?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>postbox</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/05/more-postbox-2-5-teases/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Handling Reference Emails</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/handling-reference-emails/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to refer to your email. (I've written about this &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/06/the-read-once-email-client-and-reference-emails/"&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's to integrate comments from a bunch of people while you're editing a report, or it's a set of mails with instructions for something, like how to configure &amp;amp; install a source code package or submit expense reports in the new system. These emails could all be in one thread, but just as often it's a few mails spread throughout several threads and scattered in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good mail client should make it easy to keep arbitrary groups of messages visible for reference. Since they're reference emails, you're just reading them, and the display shouldn't really be more than the text of the mail. You should be able to fit a few of these on screen without overlapping what you're actually working on, and you don't need a big toolbar with a bunch of actions that won't be happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm doing something in another app, I want to arrange my reference mails in an empty part of the screen, then not click back over to the mail client until I'm ready to close them. The faster it is to set up this display and get on with things, the better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look at how a few existing clients support this kind of thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Gmail&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to open a conversation and refer to it, and you can hide the body of messages that aren't relevant. But you can't move things around, so if it's a really long thread, you might be in for some scrolling. If you want to refer to more than one thread, you will have to open each in its own window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Apple Mail&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of its lack of a conversation-style thread view, the way to do this is to just open separate windows for each message. You can't look at a single thread in one window - have to open N windows for N messages. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Mail is what I use most often, when I have this problem I always end up with a flock of windows, and lots of clicking, scrolling and cmd-tabbing around to see what I need, followed by looking at all my open windows and trying not to close any unrelated drafts or accidentally send or delete something important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Postbox &amp;amp; Thunderbird&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience with Postbox is similar to, but a little worse than GMail.
In Postbox, there's a thread view where I can hide uninteresting messages like GMail, but if I want to pop the thread out into a separate window, I can't - only single messages can be popped into separate windows. I can make tabs with the thread view by double-clicking on a thread, but I can't figure out how to get a new window. Of course, if I need to see multiple emails at once, tabs are no good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird is basically the same, except at least in 3.0.4, the default view when you select a thread is less useful than Postbox's - it looks more like a debug dump of the message's text than a well-designed display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;MailMate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MailMate is similar to Postbox &amp;amp; Thunderbird - except that you get a nice linear conversation-style view with any selection, not just a single thread. (Postbox has a nice view but only for a thread, and TBird shows you any selection but not a nice view.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, as with those others, the linear conversation view can't be popped into its own reading-oriented window, and it's strictly linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think any of the clients I looked at have a good solution for this. Is that a problem? Is this actually important? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think so. I bet if you think about when you actually look at an email, it's usually one of three times - when you first read it, as you write a reply to it, and when you're searching for it later. In both of the second two cases, I've found that I often have more than one mail or thread that I want to look at while I write or do something in another app, and a dedicated view to support that would be great. I could search through just those messages. I could minimize or move them all at once. Just think of the possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if it's easy to keep this set of emails around for later reference without cluttering up my screen in the meantime - and without actually moving the messages into some separate folder on my server - that'd be really great. Because you always have another expense report to file, and really, who wants to memorize &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; procedure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this far, and please feel free to leave a comment - am I missing something great in one of these clients?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>email</category><category>gmail</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>postbox</category><category>thunderbird</category><category>thunderbird-3</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/handling-reference-emails/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 16:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Merging mikechecksmail</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/merging-mikechecksmail/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/i-have-a-minor-obsession-with-email-clie/"&gt;decided&lt;/a&gt; to start a separate blog called 'mikechecksmail' on Tumblr to talk about the details of mail clients on OS X. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I posted a few real articles there, then let things sit for a while as a dissertation, a new house, and a new baby have taken up my free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've now decided to keep occasionally writing about email, just here at my good old personal blog. So I've imported the old posts from Tumblr, and anything new will be here. Hopefully having just one place for things will make it easier to actually write anything at all. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/merging-mikechecksmail/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 21:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quote: Talking tools with Shawn Blanc</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/08/i-think-the-less-an-email-application-does-the-better-feature-rich-ones-only-encourage-users-to-move-in-id-rather-spend-my-time-somewhere-else/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the less an email application does the better — feature-rich ones only encourage users to move in. I’d rather spend my time somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nerdgap.com/post/941093776/talking-tools-with-shawn-blanc"&gt;from nerdgap.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mikechecksmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/08/i-think-the-less-an-email-application-does-the-better-feature-rich-ones-only-encourage-users-to-move-in-id-rather-spend-my-time-somewhere-else/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 19:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A quick note about Mobile Me Mail beta</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/a-quick-note-about-mobile-me-mail-beta/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/mobileme/news/2010/05/the-next-mobileme-mail-now-in-beta.html"&gt;A quick note about Mobile Me Mail beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple's Mobile Me mail - a webmail that always struck me as trying too hard to be like a desktop mail client - has been re-designed, and it added two features that I completely agree with in a mail client - widescreen view (a message should be the entire height of a window) and a one-click archive button, to help achieve &lt;a href="http://inboxzero.com"&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/a&gt; as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/a-quick-note-about-mobile-me-mail-beta/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 20:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brent Simmons, 2004: the RSS router</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/httpinessentialcom20040525rssrouter/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href="http://inessential.com/2004/05/25/rss_router"&gt;http://inessential.com/2004/05/25/rss_router&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a post from the recesses of memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2004, Brent Simmons said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… your feedreader, like your browser and email app, is a hub of information. It makes sense to want to route information from the hub to other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great point - and I'd like to expand on it. I think it goes further than just being able to send data from your email client to other programs. Data should be easier to send in &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most email clients want to be your only interface to your mail data. Since email communication can affect everything we do on a workstation, every program should be able to look at and update your email store, even triggering checks or controlling how you are notified of new messages. What program is better able to determine what you're likely focused on than the one you're currently using?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to handle this would involve some system-level support, so the largest set of applications could use it. I'm not holding my breath…&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>brent_simmons</category><category>email</category><category>mail_framework</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>system_support</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/httpinessentialcom20040525rssrouter/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 23:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I have a minor obsession with email clie...</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/i-have-a-minor-obsession-with-email-clie/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I have a minor obsession with email clients. I'm fascinated with how people use email and how clients have (and haven't) evolved over the last 40 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started a separate blog on Tumblr to explore email clients, called &lt;a href="http://mikechecksmail.tumblr.com/"&gt;mike checks mail&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to look at clients available now on OS X, and discuss their features and their flaws. It's basically very focused app criticism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few posts have focused on the three free apps I use daily - Apple Mail, GMail and Thunderbird. Eventually I want to explore the other major mail clients currently on the market, including Entourage, Postbox, Eudora, and Outspring. I'd also like to dive into other platforms, to avoid reinventing something smart that's been in (say) emacs for 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look, and &lt;a href="http://mikechecksmail.tumblr.com/ask/"&gt;send me questions and suggestions for topics&lt;/a&gt;. Let's geek out on mail clients…&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mikechecksmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/i-have-a-minor-obsession-with-email-clie/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 18:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>