<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (misfeature)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 10:00:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Send again</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/send-again.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l0ko62FuR81qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Mail's "Send again" feature is handy - it takes a message and creates a duplicate of it, ready to either edit or re-send exactly as-is. It's a bit of a mystery, though, and I bet it isn't used much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the wording and keyboard shortcut don't say enough about what's really about to happen. You could be forgiven for guessing that since ⌘-D sends new mails out onto the wire, it'll just send the old mail - unedited - out on the wire, too.
There's no hint that you get to edit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also the possibility for error, since pressing ⌘-D once gives you a new mail with the old contents, which a second ⌘-D will send right away, with no undo. (Lack of undo in sending is a topic for another post, of course)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also unexpected because of the name, the message doesn't have to be one you sent. If you invoke "Send again" on a message you received, you'll get a new message with the same recipients, from you. I'm having a hard time imagining why I'd ever use this. Maybe it'd save a copy and paste when sending a copy of something that I don't want to just forward, but that's a stretch. How often does that happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a handy feature, but it needs a better name and a better shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it handy? Sometimes I write a draft of an email to the outside world, then send it to team members for review. Then later, I want to edit that draft, incorporate their suggestions and send it off anew. That's when I use "Send again". But I only discovered it by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this use case, this seems like a feature that probably isn't worth the effort and extra UI clutter.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>clutter</category><category>misfeature</category><category>send-again</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/send-again.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 20:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>