<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (mozilla-labs)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 09:12:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mozilla Raindrop</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2010/04/mozilla-raindrop.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I noticed the &lt;a href="http://labs.mozilla.com/raindrop/"&gt;Mozilla Raindrop&lt;/a&gt; project. It's an interesting project in Mozilla Labs by the Thunderbird team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's trying to rethink how messaging (in general, not just email) should work - using open web technologies. On the surface it sounds like Google Wave, but I'd say it's aiming a little lower - trying to take existing protocols and build software that handles them all together in a better way. I also think it's a better approach than Wave, focusing on designing a single artifact that people will want to use instead of a framework technology demo, which is what Wave always seemed to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like it's not intended to be a native desktop (or mobile) client - they mention running it on servers, and it depends on Python and CouchDB, which would preclude it running on the iPhone OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like about it is the way they're trying to use a classification of emails - obviously, not all mails are equal. They fall somewhere in a range between spam and important personal (or work) messages. A big class is "bulk" mail - mail that's useful but not necessarily of a conversation involving you. Mailing lists, promotional mails you've asked for, facebook/twitter notifications might all fall into this category, and it's a great idea for a mailer to do something different with them. At the least, it should let you ignore them if you're just trying to do a quick processing pass of new mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://blogs.mozillamessaging.com/raindropdesign/"&gt;Raindrop design blog&lt;/a&gt; has some good posts (with plenty of screenshots) outlining their current approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>bulk-mail</category><category>mozilla</category><category>mozilla-labs</category><category>raindrop</category><category>wave</category><category>webmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/posts/2010/04/mozilla-raindrop.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>