<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (music)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/music.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for June 27, 2014</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2014/06/links-for-June-27-2014/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://opentuner.org/"&gt;OpenTuner by jansel&lt;/a&gt;
    "OpenTuner is a new framework for building domain-specific multi-objective program autotuners. OpenTuner supports fully customizable configuration representations, an extensible technique representation to allow for domain-specific techniques, and an easy to use interface for communicating with the tuned program. A key capability inside OpenTuner is the use of ensembles of disparate search techniques simultaneously, techniques which perform well will receive larger testing budgets and techniques which perform poorly will be disabled." -- This looks really useful. I started on something like this long ago at LLNL, but since I was so young I focused mostly on fancy plots and designing a language for describing experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/95534178"&gt;Paper to Plants on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;
    A really cute video about a game that seems pretty charming. I'm still not sold on little kids using iPads so much, I'm told it's bad for their eye development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.computingcomfort.org/create2.asp"&gt;Ergonomic Workspace Planner Tool | ComputingComfort.org&lt;/a&gt;
    Use this to figure out the optimal height of your standing desk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mbutterick.github.io/pollen/doc/"&gt;pollen&lt;/a&gt;
    Write web based books in racket&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dealloc.me/2014/05/24/opendata-house-hunting/"&gt;Finding the perfect house using open data — dealloc.me&lt;/a&gt;
    A guy builds a map of available houses in Portland that match his desires. Seems like a good real estate agent should do this for you - but how do you know you've got a good one? I guess you have to write some code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://billmill.org/pymag-trees/"&gt;Drawing Presentable Trees&lt;/a&gt;
    "When I needed to draw some trees for a project I was doing, I assumed that there would be a classic, easy algorithm for drawing neat trees. What I found instead was much more interesting: not only is tree layout an NP-complete problem1, but there is a long and interesting history behind tree-drawing algorithms. I will use the history of tree drawing algorithms to introduce central concepts one at a time, using each of them to build up to a complete O(n) algorithm for drawing attractive diagrams of trees." -- I've always wondered what a good way to do this would be. Knew it had to be a solved problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://againstallgrain.com/2013/10/12/grain-free-oatmeal-raisin-cookies/"&gt;Grain-Free Oatmeal Raisin Cookies | Against All Grain - Delectable paleo recipes to eat &amp;amp; feel great&lt;/a&gt;
    If you want oatmeal-raisin but you're trying to avoid oats and sugar, these are really quite good. The coconut makes a great texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/family/2014/06/lev_grossman_on_his_daughter_lily_how_being_a_father_ruined_my_life_and.html"&gt;Lev Grossman on his daughter, Lily: How being a father ruined my life and made me a better writer.&lt;/a&gt;
    A really heartfelt story about becoming a dad and getting your act together. Now that I have kids I'm a total sucker for this kind of article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hal.archives-ouvertes.fr/inria-00555588/"&gt;HAL :: [inria-00555588, version 1] A comprehensive study of Convergent and Commutative Replicated Data Types&lt;/a&gt;
    Formal exploration of sync-able data types. Abstract: "Eventual consistency aims to ensure that replicas of some mutable shared object converge without foreground synchronisation. Previous approaches to eventual consistency are ad-hoc and error-prone. We study a principled approach: to base the design of shared data types on some simple formal conditions that are sufficient to guarantee eventual consistency. We call these types Convergent or Commutative Replicated Data Types (CRDTs). This paper formalises asynchronous object replication, either state based or operation based, and provides a sufficient condition appropriate for each case. It describes several useful CRDTs, including container data types supporting both \add and \remove operations with clean semantics, and more complex types such as graphs, montonic DAGs, and sequences. It discusses some properties needed to implement non-trivial CRDTs."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dev.stephendiehl.com/hask/#intro"&gt;What I Wish I Knew When Learning Haskell 2.1 ( Stephen Diehl )&lt;/a&gt;
    Nice quick article with practical tips for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.psmag.com/navigation/business-economics/talent-migration-work-creative-much-new-york-poor-pittsburgh-rich-82894/"&gt;Not So Much 'New York Poor' as 'Pittsburgh Rich' - Pacific Standard: The Science of Society&lt;/a&gt;
    You can get a lot for your money in Pittsburgh, and lots of other places throughout the US. I'm from Pgh, and have fond memories. I'd consider moving back there if they could fix the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aphyr.com/posts/317-call-me-maybe-elasticsearch"&gt;Call me maybe: Elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt;
    Part of a series of irreverent but thorough explorations of various popular distributed systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://m.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/"&gt;What Do We Save When We Save the Internet&lt;/a&gt;
    So as you proceed with your protests, I wonder if you might also ask, quietly, to yourself even, what new growth might erupt if we let the Internet as we know it burn. Shouldn't we at least ponder the question? Perhaps we’d be better off tolerating the venial regret of having lost something than suffering the mortal regret of enduring it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.musanim.com/"&gt;Music Animation Machine — "Music Worth Watching"&lt;/a&gt;
    Old stuff, but great. Couldn't believe I hadn't bookmarked it long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://serialized.net/2013/03/moving-from-octopress-to-nikola/"&gt;Moving from Octopress to Nikola | serialized.net&lt;/a&gt;
    This post and a few tweaks got me into nikola without much hassle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>acheme</category><category>algorithms</category><category>analysis</category><category>app</category><category>art</category><category>autotuning</category><category>blogging</category><category>calculator</category><category>constraints</category><category>cookie</category><category>CRDT</category><category>criticism</category><category>culture</category><category>data</category><category>data-structures</category><category>diagram</category><category>ergonomics</category><category>estate</category><category>eventual-consistency</category><category>fatherhood</category><category>finance</category><category>gluten-free</category><category>graphics</category><category>growing</category><category>haskell</category><category>housing</category><category>howto</category><category>internet</category><category>kids</category><category>language</category><category>maps</category><category>merging</category><category>music</category><category>nikola</category><category>oatmeal</category><category>octopress</category><category>optimization</category><category>paleo</category><category>parenting</category><category>performance</category><category>pittsburgh</category><category>plants</category><category>programming</category><category>publishing</category><category>quickref</category><category>racket</category><category>real</category><category>recipe</category><category>reference</category><category>research</category><category>solver</category><category>sync</category><category>tree</category><category>tuning</category><category>typesetting</category><category>up</category><category>video</category><category>visualization</category><category>workstation</category><category>writing</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2014/06/links-for-June-27-2014/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 19:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links: Hacking, Music in Python, Rust &amp; unitasking</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/04/links-hacking-music-in-python-rust-unitaskimg/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for April 5th through April 6th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lemire.me/blog/archives/2011/06/06/why-i-still-program/"&gt;Why I still program&lt;/a&gt; - "I believe that the rejection of programming as a lower activity can be explained by the Theory of the leisure class. In effect, we do not seek utility but prestige. There is no prestige in tool-making, cooking or farming. To maximize your prestige, you must rise up to the leisure class: you work must not be immediately useful."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lemire.me/blog/archives/2012/03/20/from-counting-citations-to-measuring-usage-help-needed/"&gt;From counting citations to measuring usage (help needed!)&lt;/a&gt; - Building a Better Citation Index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mailplaneapp.com/blog/entry/workhacks.com_top_3_gmail_management_apps_for_mac"&gt;workhacks.com: Top 3 Gmail Management Apps for Mac - Mailplane Blog&lt;/a&gt; - includes a list of gmail plugins that look useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://prezjordan.github.com/Melopy/"&gt;Melopy&lt;/a&gt; - 
&lt;code&gt;  &lt;br&gt;
    """
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from melopy import Melopy
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m = Melopy('mysong')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.add_quarter_note('A4')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.add_quarter_note('C#5')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.add_quarter_note('E5')
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m.render()
    [==================================================] 100%
    Done
    """
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://doc.rust-lang.org/doc/tutorial.html#expression-syntax"&gt;Rust Language Tutorial: Expression Syntax&lt;/a&gt; - Starts out good, but the "leave out a semicolon to return a value" leaves a bad taste. Why overload semicolons like that? Why not just use 'ret'?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.deliberatism.com/blog/forget-self-improvement/"&gt;Forget Self-Improvement&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/schwartz/2012/03/the-magic-of-doing-one-thing-a.html"&gt;The Magic of Doing One Thing at a Time - Tony Schwartz - Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt; - A few good points on avoiding multitasking burnout. Nothing too new, but maybe if people keep repeating it in places like HBR, then it'll start to become conventional business wisdom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>business</category><category>citation</category><category>email</category><category>gmail</category><category>impact</category><category>libraries</category><category>links</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>multitasking</category><category>music</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>productivity</category><category>programming</category><category>publication</category><category>python</category><category>ranking</category><category>research</category><category>rust</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/04/links-hacking-music-in-python-rust-unitaskimg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 23:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links: Haskell, Music OCD Tools, Terrorism, Probability for Ranking things</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/04/links-haskell-music-ocd-tools-terrorism-probability-for-ranking-things/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for March 30th through April 3rd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://magicmaps.evanmiller.org/"&gt;Magic Maps: Now You See It.&lt;/a&gt; - Very cool app for working with maps and time series data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://evanmiller.org/how-not-to-sort-by-average-rating.html"&gt;How Not To Sort By Average Rating&lt;/a&gt; - Shows the best way to sort by positive/negative rankings that is robust to small sample sizes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://m.foreignaffairs.com/articles/66186/john-mueller-and-mark-g-stewart/hardly-existential"&gt;terrorism hardly existential threat. 2010&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mailplaneapp.com/blog/entry/workhacks.com_top_3_gmail_management_apps_for_mac/#When:12:06:06Z"&gt;workhacks.com: Top 3 Gmail Management Apps for Mac&lt;/a&gt; includes a list of gmail plugins that look useful &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.yesodweb.com/"&gt;Yesod Web Framework for Haskell&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://beets.radbox.org/"&gt;beets: the music geek's media organizer&lt;/a&gt; - The purpose of beets is to get your music collection right once and for all. It catalogs your collection, automatically improving its metadata as it goes using the MusicBrainz database. (It also downloads cover art for albums it imports.) Then it provides a bouquet of tools for manipulating and accessing your music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because beets is designed as a library, it can do almost anything you can imagine for your music collection. Via plugins, beets becomes a panacea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embed and extract album art from files' tags.
Listen to your library with a music player that speaks the MPD protocol and works with a staggering variety of interfaces.
Fetch lyrics for all your songs from databases on the Web.
Manage your MusicBrainz music collection.
Analyze music files' metadata from the command line.
Clean up crufty tags left behind by other, less-awesome tools.
Browse your music library graphically through a Web browser and play it in any browser that supports HTML5 Audio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>apps</category><category>framework</category><category>gmail</category><category>haskell</category><category>links</category><category>maps</category><category>music</category><category>ocd</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>plugins</category><category>policy</category><category>programming</category><category>ranking</category><category>score</category><category>statistics</category><category>tagging</category><category>terrorism</category><category>web</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/04/links-haskell-music-ocd-tools-terrorism-probability-for-ranking-things/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links for September 4th through September 6th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/09/links-for-september-4th-through-september-6th/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for September 4th through September 6th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.indiewire.com/pressplay/archives/video_essay_matthias_stork_calls_out_the_chaos_cinema/"&gt;VIDEO ESSAY: CHAOS CINEMA: The decline and fall of action filmmaking &amp;gt; Press Play&lt;/a&gt; - A great essay, essentially anti-shakycam and fastcuts. Nice to see the example of Ronin for a slow-cut, well set up sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lilypond.org/examples.html"&gt;LilyPond - Music notation for everyone: Examples&lt;/a&gt; - music notation markup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>links</category><category>music</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>typesetting</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/09/links-for-september-4th-through-september-6th/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fresh Air: Stan Getz in the '50s</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/fresh-air-stan-getz-in-the-50s/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some great samples and historical tidbits from Fresh Air: &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/03/18/134652613/before-ipanema-stan-getzs-exquisite-quintets?ft=1&amp;amp;f;=13&amp;amp;sc;=17"&gt;Before Ipanema: Stan Getz's exquisite quintets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before he was famous for popularizing bossa nova with "The Girl from Ipanema" in the early 1960s, saxophonist Stan Getz recorded with small jazz groups all through the '50s. Jazz critic Kevin Whitehead says a new reissue shows Getz was one of the best at playing pretty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really love Fresh Air. I used to listen to it every day after school while playing Crystal Quest in my room. Every time I hear Terry Gross' voice, I get a bit of a rush like I'm goofing off instead of doing my homework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>music</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/fresh-air-stan-getz-in-the-50s/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 17:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>iTunes Skip Count</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/10/itunes-skip-count/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been mentioned before, for example &lt;a href="http://digg.com/apple/New_iTunes_7_SKIP_COUNT_feature"&gt;on Digg&lt;/a&gt;, but iTunes 7 has a new feature that counts the number of times you've &lt;em&gt;skipped&lt;/em&gt; a track, which is defined as playing the song for at least two seconds but no longer than twenty (after which it is counted as played fully).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm curious how they chose twenty seconds as the cutoff - when I was working on an (unreleased and unfinished) project for generating smart shuffles, I defined skips as not listening past the first fifteen seconds, but didn't count a full play until the song ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an interesting feature, and it's apparently kept up to date by some iPods, so I can see it helping me keep bad songs off my small iPod by using it in a smart playlist rule. However, often I find myself skipping songs I really like because I'm just not feeling them at the moment. So - how about the option of a smart playlist rule that lets me define a skip percentage? If I skip a song far more often than I play it, then it's a pretty good bet I don't need it on my iPod.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>mac</category><category>music</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/10/itunes-skip-count/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 02:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Matt Pond PA</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/03/matt-pond-pa/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I meant to post this just after the show, but I didn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href="http://mattpondpa.com/"&gt;Matt Pond PA&lt;/a&gt; play on March 7th at the Epicentre in Mira Mesa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The band sounded great, fitting a sometimes symphonic sound from a few band members into a smallish low-ceilinged venue (okay, teen center). I was impressed that their sometimes melancholy songs translated so well to a live performance, and as usual it was fantastic to see actual people play favorite familiar songs in person. As compared to their albums, live, they &lt;em&gt;rocked&lt;/em&gt; a little more - which is only right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the band fails to even mention the date on their running tour blog, and I think I know why. Mira Mesa in general, and the Epicentre in particular, occupy an all-too familiar spot right in the nexus of &lt;em&gt;lame&lt;/em&gt;. It's hard for me not to feel a little sad whenever I drive through the place, a plateau of asphalt wedged between freeways and topped with a layer-cake of condos, strip malls and "communities". The Epicentre is not a bar or any kind of concert hall - it is a teen center directly across from the local high school. The bathrooms smelled like chalk and institutional cleaners, and although I'm sure I'd have visited the place if it'd existed near my high school, it was clearly trying too hard to be both cool and safe, two things which can never coexist, especially if you're a minor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a little embarrassed for my adopted city because too many bands will experience San Diego as a place where they draw ten percent of their usual crowds and are forced to play at the diner from Saved by the Bell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Matt Pond PA was very good, and I really hope they don't hold a grudge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>music</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/03/matt-pond-pa/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2006 05:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Takk… etc.</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/01/takk-etc/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought three new albums with my iTunes gift card this Christmas, and I thought I'd share how they've turned out so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takk… by Sigur Ros. I bought this because I liked their last album, the parentheses one, and because John Allison's &lt;a href="http://www.scarygoround.com/?date=20051226"&gt;hilarious year end album review&lt;/a&gt; seemed to imply it was more of the same: "Everyone is fooled!" I find that I do like it just as much, but unlike all those Untitled songs in the last one, I don't mind listening to these songs when the sun is out. A fun game for casual fans is to play songs from the two albums together at random, and try to guess which album they're from. I call this the "Coldplay game".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late Registration by Kanye West. Everyone says it's great, and I don't listen to radio or watch MTV anyway, so I can't be annoyed by overplayed singles. I really like this album. Great for playing really loud while driving someone else's car across the desert at perfectly legal speeds. Luckily I live in Southern California, so nobody looks at me funny when my pale white fingers crank the volume on the way to my hockey game. I think my favorite track here is "Addiction".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Straw by Snow Patrol. I've listened to it a few times already, it seems like there's a few great songs in there, a few I won't ever remember, and I have a nagging feeling that this will become another Josh Joplin Group, who I loved for three weeks and almost always skip past now. Which would be sad. If there was one song to get from this album, I think it'd be "Chocolate", not "Run", which was the big single. So there it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>music</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/01/takk-etc/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 04:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>