<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (notification)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 12:24:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Let's talk some more email philosophy. An email client should help you quickly get through new email</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/lets-talk-some-more-email-philosophy-an-email-client-should-help-you-quickly-get-through-new-email/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Let's talk some more email philosophy. An email client should help you quickly get through new emails, on your schedule, and turn them into whatever you need them to be once you've read them. Then it should shut up until you call it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I'll point at &lt;a href="http://inboxzero.com/"&gt;Merlin Mann&lt;/a&gt; as my original inspiration, and if you want to hear more about the reasons behind this line of thought, go listen to his recent podcast appearances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further - I'm against unread counts, against new-mail sounds, against pop-up notification of new mail. I can't think of a job you could have where there's a good reason you should be interrupted by an email client for every new message. Sure, some things are important and ought to interrupt you - but there are a host of better technologies for urgent communication - IM, SMS, Phone calls, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm for search, against filing. If you're shuffling email into folders, part of what you're doing is building an index. Computers know how to index text, and they can do it faster and more completely than you can, so stop wasting your time - especially if you're just filing it according to data that's already in the message, like sender or date. If your filing system is adding some information to each message, then a client should just let you add that info quickly and then index it for you. Not enough clients do this well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, like many people, I work at a big company that runs its own email infrastructure and won't be giving control to Google any time soon. This means that while GMail is an interesting case study and a useful option for personal email, I need to use another client for most of my email. That's why mikechecksmail is about desktop mail clients. I use a Mac, and so it's about Mac desktop mail clients. That said, I won't ignore other systems - good ideas are good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>filing</category><category>gmail</category><category>inbox-zero</category><category>minimalism</category><category>notification</category><category>philosophy</category><category>quiet</category><category>search</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/lets-talk-some-more-email-philosophy-an-email-client-should-help-you-quickly-get-through-new-email/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Notifications and Distraction in Webapps</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/08/from-blog-abi-sh-silent-diving-seagulls-an-xmpp-interface-for-desktop-notifications/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Found via Hacker News:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.abi.sh/2009/silent-diving-seagulls/"&gt;abi | blog  » Introducing Silent Diving Seagulls: An XMPP Interface for Desktop Notifications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here is that you can use XMPP to let web apps pop up Growl (or libnotify or Snarl, etc) notifications on your desktop. This is a pretty cool hack, and it seems like the right solution to getting notifications from the cloud onto your desktop - as Abi mentions in the post, you don't want direct connections to Growl and you also don't want every site writing its own notify app. It's also another step in blurring the lines between web apps and desktop apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I think the majority of uses for this kind of notification are distracting and unproductive. The example Abi uses is getting updates from friendfeed - you'd get a notification every time one of your friends does anything on friendfeed. If you think hearing a beep every time you get new mail is distracting, just wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the only use I've found for notifications is to let you know you can get back to work when something long you've been waiting for finishes. I wrote more about this in &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/2008/08/28/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/"&gt;'go juggle': an attention callback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So notification technology is useful, and it's cool to see web apps getting into it, but please, web or desktop – ship with notifications off. Let's not have the default behavior of your app be distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edit&lt;/strong&gt;: In the &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=755507"&gt;HN thread on Silent Diving Seagulls&lt;/a&gt;, abi notes that he's sensitive to the distraction this can cause, and makes some good points about why it's still a good idea. The best point - if everyone adopts something like this, email goes back to being email and not an overloaded notification scheme.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>desktopvswebapps</category><category>focus</category><category>growl</category><category>notification</category><category>xmpp</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/08/from-blog-abi-sh-silent-diving-seagulls-an-xmpp-interface-for-desktop-notifications/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 16:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>