<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (philosophy)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/philosophy.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for mid-March see scalable python around corners. And Future Spies on Facebook!</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/03/links-for-mid-march-see-scalable-python-around-corners-and-future-spies-on-facebook/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for March 18th through March 26th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/3/26/7-years-of-youtube-scalability-lessons-in-30-minutes.html"&gt;7 Years of YouTube Scalability Lessons in 30 Minutes&lt;/a&gt; - Notes from a PyCon talk about the very pragmatic design philosophy at YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/bkad/discoball"&gt;bkad/discoball * GitHub&lt;/a&gt; - shell tool to match and colorize lines of text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pragprog.com/book/kcdc/the-developer-s-code"&gt;The Pragmatic Bookshelf | The Developer's Code&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/news/how-to-see-around-corners-1.10258"&gt;How to see around corners : Nature News &amp;amp; Comment&lt;/a&gt; - And we thought the future was flying cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2012/03/19/cia_internet_of_things/page2.html"&gt;ARM's ultra-low-power fridge-puter chips: Just what the CIA ordered • The Register&lt;/a&gt; - Out of context interesting quote: "The spy boss was chiefly concerned with the huge amounts of data that can be collected from American citizens who intend to become CIA agents - in an age when parents set up Twitter and Tumblr accounts for their newborns, managing the identities of future operatives suddenly becomes non-trivial."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://reprog.wordpress.com/2012/02/27/who-needs-access-you-need-access/"&gt;Who needs access? You need access!&lt;/a&gt; - new site about open access to research aimed at lay people (I think)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>architecture</category><category>ARM</category><category>CIA</category><category>colorize</category><category>future</category><category>imaging</category><category>internet-of-things</category><category>laser</category><category>links</category><category>logging</category><category>openaccess</category><category>philosophy</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>programming</category><category>python</category><category>research</category><category>scalability</category><category>shell</category><category>spies</category><category>spycam</category><category>wisdom</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/03/links-for-mid-march-see-scalable-python-around-corners-and-future-spies-on-facebook/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Links for January 3rd through January 5th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-january-3rd-through-january-5th/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My shared links for January 3rd through January 5th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://edge.org/responses/what-scientific-concept-would-improve-everybodys-cognitive-toolkit"&gt;2011 Annual Question | Edge : "what scientific concept would improve everybody's cognitive toolkit"&lt;/a&gt; - As usual more thought provoking essays than will fit in my head, but seriously, what is "A Proxemic of Urban Sexuality" getting at?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mhall119.com/2012/01/simplified-unity-lens-development-with-singlet/"&gt;Simplified Unity Lens Development with Singlet | Michael Hall's Blog&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/llvm-py/"&gt;llvm-py - Python bindings for LLVM - Google Project Hosting&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mython.org/"&gt;The Mython Programming Language&lt;/a&gt; - "Mython is an extensible variant of the Python programming language. Mython makes Python extensible by adding two things: parametric quotation statement, and compile-time metaprogramming. The parametric quote statement is simply syntactic sugar for saying "run some function on this embedded string". Compile-time metaprogramming allows you to evaluate that function on the embedded string at compile time. This gives you added choice, both in terms of what your code looks like, and when you want to evaluate that code."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.solarisinternals.com/wiki/index.php/Solaris_Internals_and_Performance_FAQ"&gt;Solaris Internals and Performance FAQ - Siwiki&lt;/a&gt; - Main Page for Solaris Internals Wiki. Tons of info about Solaris' er, Internals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dtrace</category><category>essays</category><category>lens</category><category>links</category><category>llvm</category><category>metaprogramming</category><category>mython</category><category>oracle</category><category>performance</category><category>philosophy</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>python</category><category>science</category><category>solaris</category><category>sun</category><category>ubuntu</category><category>unity</category><category>wiki</category><category>zfs</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2012/01/links-for-january-3rd-through-january-5th/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 20:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Let's talk some more email philosophy. An email client should help you quickly get through new email</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/lets-talk-some-more-email-philosophy-an-email-client-should-help-you-quickly-get-through-new-email/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's talk some more email philosophy. An email client should help you quickly get through new emails, on your schedule, and turn them into whatever you need them to be once you've read them. Then it should shut up until you call it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I'll point at &lt;a href="http://inboxzero.com/"&gt;Merlin Mann&lt;/a&gt; as my original inspiration, and if you want to hear more about the reasons behind this line of thought, go listen to his recent podcast appearances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further - I'm against unread counts, against new-mail sounds, against pop-up notification of new mail. I can't think of a job you could have where there's a good reason you should be interrupted by an email client for every new message. Sure, some things are important and ought to interrupt you - but there are a host of better technologies for urgent communication - IM, SMS, Phone calls, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm for search, against filing. If you're shuffling email into folders, part of what you're doing is building an index. Computers know how to index text, and they can do it faster and more completely than you can, so stop wasting your time - especially if you're just filing it according to data that's already in the message, like sender or date. If your filing system is adding some information to each message, then a client should just let you add that info quickly and then index it for you. Not enough clients do this well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, like many people, I work at a big company that runs its own email infrastructure and won't be giving control to Google any time soon. This means that while GMail is an interesting case study and a useful option for personal email, I need to use another client for most of my email. That's why mikechecksmail is about desktop mail clients. I use a Mac, and so it's about Mac desktop mail clients. That said, I won't ignore other systems - good ideas are good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>filing</category><category>gmail</category><category>inbox-zero</category><category>minimalism</category><category>notification</category><category>philosophy</category><category>quiet</category><category>search</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/lets-talk-some-more-email-philosophy-an-email-client-should-help-you-quickly-get-through-new-email/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why mikechecksmail</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/why-mikechecksmail/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that email clients are important, and worth a little criticism. We all use email, and lots of us complain about it - especially professionals.
It's such a critical tool for our jobs, and it's frustrating when it doesn't work as well as we'd like, or when it distracts too much when we have better things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's my philosophy on email? If you want the original inspiration in long form, check out what Merlin Mann has been saying for years now, at &lt;a href="http://inboxzero.com/"&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/a&gt;. The short version, which might look funny on a site where I plan to talk about email clients, is that most of what people don't like about email isn't the email software's fault. If email is a huge problem for your work, you probably can't solve it with a better client. I can't agree more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that's no reason not to insist on continued improvements in the one tool every single knowledge worker uses, and that's what this site is about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>about</category><category>email</category><category>inboxzero</category><category>philosophy</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/why-mikechecksmail/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 19:39:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>