<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (postbox)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 10:00:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for June 29th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/06/links-for-june-29th.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for June 29th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www3.postbox-inc.com/?/blog/entry/postbox_2_5_now_available/"&gt;Postbox 2.5 Now Available! -- Postbox&lt;/a&gt; - Why is 64-bit support the first bullet point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chuqui.com/2011/06/avoiding-email-bankruptcy-part-1/"&gt;Avoiding email bankruptcy (part 1) - Chuqui 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Part 1 of 2: learn to recognize that email takes time and block out time to deal with it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chuqui.com/2011/06/avoiding-email-bankruptcy-part-2/"&gt;Avoiding email bankruptcy (part 2) - Chuqui 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Part 2: Chuq explains his email workflow. Nice and sane, very similar to what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>email-client</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>postbox</category><category>time-management</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/06/links-for-june-29th.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 23:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The redesigned message view in Postbox 2.5</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/05/more-postbox-2-5-teases.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The Postbox team posted another tease for their upcoming redesign in version 2.5, this time the &lt;a href="http://www3.postbox-inc.com/?/blog/entry/postbox_2_5_-_message_view_redesign/"&gt;new message view&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to re-post all of these, but I thought this one was worth pointing out because it shows some of the thinking behind the changes - and hints at an interesting design principle: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detail views that don't change visual structure when the item they're displaying changes feel faster and more solid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you agree?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>postbox</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/05/more-postbox-2-5-teases.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 04:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Postbox 2.5's New Addressing Widget</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/postbox-2-5s-new-addressing-widget.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Over at the &lt;a href="http://www.postbox-inc.com/blog"&gt;Postbox blog&lt;/a&gt;, they're teasing the upcoming version 2.5 with a post about a &lt;a href="http://www.postbox-inc.com/blog/entry/postbox_2-5_new_addressing_widget/"&gt;New Addressing Widget&lt;/a&gt;. There's only a screenshot, but it looks like a nice usability improvement - it looks more Mac-like. To and CC are in separate fields, so it's easier to add a CC without using the mouse now, and they use the token field widget (the little blue lozenge introduced in Apple Mail in 2005) to make it easier to drag around whole addresses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do say they're working on some re-styling and finishing touches - so I'll reserve judgement until I use it. For now, it's still catch-up.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>email</category><category>postbox</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/postbox-2-5s-new-addressing-widget.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 18:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Handling Reference Emails</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/handling-reference-emails.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to refer to your email. (I've written about this &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/06/the-read-once-email-client-and-reference-emails/"&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's to integrate comments from a bunch of people while you're editing a report, or it's a set of mails with instructions for something, like how to configure &amp;amp; install a source code package or submit expense reports in the new system. These emails could all be in one thread, but just as often it's a few mails spread throughout several threads and scattered in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good mail client should make it easy to keep arbitrary groups of messages visible for reference. Since they're reference emails, you're just reading them, and the display shouldn't really be more than the text of the mail. You should be able to fit a few of these on screen without overlapping what you're actually working on, and you don't need a big toolbar with a bunch of actions that won't be happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I'm doing something in another app, I want to arrange my reference mails in an empty part of the screen, then not click back over to the mail client until I'm ready to close them. The faster it is to set up this display and get on with things, the better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look at how a few existing clients support this kind of thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Gmail&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to open a conversation and refer to it, and you can hide the body of messages that aren't relevant. But you can't move things around, so if it's a really long thread, you might be in for some scrolling. If you want to refer to more than one thread, you will have to open each in its own window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Apple Mail&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of its lack of a conversation-style thread view, the way to do this is to just open separate windows for each message. You can't look at a single thread in one window - have to open N windows for N messages. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Mail is what I use most often, when I have this problem I always end up with a flock of windows, and lots of clicking, scrolling and cmd-tabbing around to see what I need, followed by looking at all my open windows and trying not to close any unrelated drafts or accidentally send or delete something important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Postbox &amp;amp; Thunderbird&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience with Postbox is similar to, but a little worse than GMail.
In Postbox, there's a thread view where I can hide uninteresting messages like GMail, but if I want to pop the thread out into a separate window, I can't - only single messages can be popped into separate windows. I can make tabs with the thread view by double-clicking on a thread, but I can't figure out how to get a new window. Of course, if I need to see multiple emails at once, tabs are no good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird is basically the same, except at least in 3.0.4, the default view when you select a thread is less useful than Postbox's - it looks more like a debug dump of the message's text than a well-designed display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;MailMate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MailMate is similar to Postbox &amp;amp; Thunderbird - except that you get a nice linear conversation-style view with any selection, not just a single thread. (Postbox has a nice view but only for a thread, and TBird shows you any selection but not a nice view.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, as with those others, the linear conversation view can't be popped into its own reading-oriented window, and it's strictly linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think any of the clients I looked at have a good solution for this. Is that a problem? Is this actually important? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think so. I bet if you think about when you actually look at an email, it's usually one of three times - when you first read it, as you write a reply to it, and when you're searching for it later. In both of the second two cases, I've found that I often have more than one mail or thread that I want to look at while I write or do something in another app, and a dedicated view to support that would be great. I could search through just those messages. I could minimize or move them all at once. Just think of the possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if it's easy to keep this set of emails around for later reference without cluttering up my screen in the meantime - and without actually moving the messages into some separate folder on my server - that'd be really great. Because you always have another expense report to file, and really, who wants to memorize &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; procedure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this far, and please feel free to leave a comment - am I missing something great in one of these clients?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>email</category><category>gmail</category><category>mikechecksmail</category><category>postbox</category><category>thunderbird</category><category>thunderbird-3</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/04/handling-reference-emails.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 16:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversation View &amp; Keeping up with Lists</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/conversation-view-keeping-up-with-lists.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Here's a set of screenshots that show how conversation view can help keeping up with a public list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been subscribed to the LLVM-dev mailing list for years in GMail, and for about a week in my mikechecksmail test account. I'm not active in the LLVM project - it's just something I want to check in on occasionally. (For a while I had a filter that popped up any mention of Fortran). So when I check in, I want to skim the threads and read anything that's interesting. Usually that means I'm finding a thread that's already pretty long and I'm reading the whole thread from the beginning the first time I see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm interested to hear if that's not how you read public high-traffic lists - do you try to keep up with all the threads as they come in? I did that for a while, but it's hard to keep up with and probably isn't actually your job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with that workflow in mind, how do our clients fare?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GMail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GMail, when you click on a new thread (aka "conversation") you get the messages all on one page, starting with the earliest - perfect for reading from the beginning. This shot shows the first couple of messages in a medium size thread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ai4mO4Al1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty good about handling quotes, too. If you're reading through an entire thread at a time, it's nice to have quoted text collapsed so you don't end up scrolling past the same paragraphs over and over. Of course, quoted text can be critical for understanding the new text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;quoted&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;quoted&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;!!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But in my judgement, barring some natural language analysis, the best default is to collapse and let the user click to expand quotes when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you return to a thread and it has new messages, it'll collapse the ones you've seen before, handy to get a quick update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ajpwBp531qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you select "Show Conversations" in the "View" menu, Postbox shows something like a conversation-view when you select an entire thread. If you don't have that option on, or you select more than one message in any other way - like shift-or-command-clicking multiple messages, you get a blank content view. Not very useful, but a minor point - after all, GMail doesn't really show the list in the same page as the content anyway, so they've avoided that design problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major problem with Postbox's conversation view - for this list-catchup task - is that it sorts the messages with the newest ones at the top. This is exactly the wrong thing for reading a whole thread, and I couldn't find a way to change this sort order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what it looks like on that same thread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ajxnHkKi1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple other minor nitpicks - the info pane with the sender and links on the right-hand side only shows its info for the most recent message - if you want that info for another message, you have to select just that message in the list view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you revisit the thread, it marks every message as read, and there's no way to see what's new:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ajzroxSb1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still looking at the thread when new messages in that thread come in, it'll give you a nice alert and lets you refresh the view, but then the problem is still there - it's up to you to see what's new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird 3 has a summary view, but it's not thread-centric.
It just shows the sender, date and first few lines (smashed together without newlines) of each message you've selected. If you select a thread, it's kind of like a conversation view, but if you select multiple unrelated messages, it'll just show the messages in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1ak9yEo0u1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly there's some room for improvement there. I won't pick on it too much, except to say that smashing the text together for a summary makes this view basically useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Mail doesn't really try to give you a summary of a thread or a conversation view - it'll show which mails are new, but then you have to click through to an individual view of each message. Here's what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l1akg4XWv41qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't sloppy like Thunderbird's view, but it's not very useful either. For this and other reasons, keeping up with public mailing lists in Apple Mail is pretty painful. That's why I moved most of my list subscriptions over to GMail a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>apple-mail</category><category>conversation-view</category><category>gmail</category><category>lists</category><category>postbox</category><category>thunderbird</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/conversation-view-keeping-up-with-lists.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 19:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Postbox</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/postbox.html</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've grabbed a copy of &lt;a href="http://postbox-inc.com/"&gt;Postbox&lt;/a&gt;, so I can add it to the list of clients I'm poking around. It's cross-platform, based on Thunderbird, so it shares a lot of its foundations, such as a tabbed, multi-pane interface. The settings in particular are very similar to Thunderbird 3, with just the occasional tweak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, they've clearly put a lot of effort into a nice face-lift and some added features. Some of the features remind me of &lt;a href="http://chandlerproject.org/"&gt;Chandler&lt;/a&gt;, such as the ability to quickly make a message into a 'todo', and to edit messages in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be curious to see how many of these differences work. Editing messages in place doesn't seem like something I'm ever going to want to do, but I'd be interested to hear why someone else would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also added twitter and facebook support, which I haven't investigated yet, but at first kind of goes against my email client religion - I'm not convinced that adding new protocols is the way to make clients better. However, there's definitely a growing feeling that we have too many inboxes now. That's a theme echoed in the &lt;a href="https://mozillalabs.com/raindrop/"&gt;Mozilla Raindrop&lt;/a&gt; project, too. So maybe this will appeal to people who want everything dumped into one program. For now, I'm not sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also one of the few clients you can actually &lt;em&gt;pay&lt;/em&gt; for, which is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To revisit a couple of earlier topics, the unread count badge is the same as in Thunderbird 3 - no way to turn it off. (And they've kept the option to bounce and annoy on new mail. I didn't try it to see if it works.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model for allowing images in HTML mail is a small improvement on Thunderbird 3. You can allow it once, or just whitelist the sender - you will still get the sender as a full entry in your Contacts list, but it adds it quietly, without bugging you for the first name of Mr. Noreply. I guess I don't mind it as much, but contact list pollution still annoys me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a screenshot of Postbox telling me it's blocked some images. You can also see their 'todo' and 'edit'  buttons - to turn the message into a todo or edit it in place, and the summary pane on the right side that shows some info about the sender and lists links and attachments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l0xkw2y44M1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this screenshot, you can see it using that pane to list some attachments. However, what it's listing is attached images that are used inline in the HTML message. I'd prefer that it didn't treat those as first-class "attachments", even though they technically are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l0xkwaHhbE1qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>attachments</category><category>chandler</category><category>html-mail</category><category>postbox</category><category>tbird-3</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/postbox.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>