<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (quiet)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/quiet.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Unread counts</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/unread-counts/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One common misguided feature of mail clients is putting an attention-grabbing red badge somewhere showing the count of unread messages in your inbox (or some other folder).
It's worst if it's on the dock badge and you don't hide the dock - then there's no way short of quitting the app to completely avoid this visual interruption. Sure you can just ignore it, but why should you have to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick survey of the three main mail clients I've been using shows that they all have some way of putting unread counts in your line of sight, and only Apple Mail (I use v 3.6 on OS X 10.5) really lets you shut it up - you can tell it not to badge the dock at all. If you had a subset of mail that really does need to interrupt you, you can also restrict the unread count to a particular smart mailbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AppleMail Quiet Prefs" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l07f5b5Zez1qz505e.tiff"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smart mailbox feature is interesting. It's hard to imagine what kind of email is just important enough to show the unread count for, but not important enough for a more obvious alert. I'm sure the feature comes from a different viewpoint on mail - perhaps the idea is that you'll never read all your messages, so you want to see a count of how many "important" ones you need to read. I think that's just treating a symptom, though, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the scale, Thunderbird 3 has no way that I can find to turn off the dock badge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="TBird dock badge" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l07fezvyeh1qz505e.tiff"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do give you a way to make it more annoying, though - you can have the dock icon bounce for every new mail! I can't think of any good reason for that, except that at some point when the dock was new, it was fun to make things bounce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tbird quiet prefs" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l07fj1MSaz1qz505e.tiff"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, GMail - I take my GMail more or less straight-up, in a dedicated browser app with no extra frills, that I wrote in 2006 (see post &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/05/webmail-is-not-web-browsing/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ). I understand that apps like &lt;a href="http://mailplaneapp.com"&gt;Mailplane&lt;/a&gt; add some nice desktop integration, and multiple account support, but I don't really need that stuff. So, assuming a basic straight-up GMail, it has no dock badge, but it does show an unread count in the title bar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="gmail unread" src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l07fvlL0011qz505e.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that'll show up in some menus and on mouse-over in Exposé, it's really not a big deal. I'd say that GMail (in the browser) and Apple Mail are about the same in terms of visual distraction, once you change the prefs in Mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd prefer that an email app didn't do anything to make all unread messages look like something important you need to fix. If I'm going to check the mail, I'll notice the messages. If I'm not about to check the mail, I don't want to know. I think this is best for everyone, too - like the insistence on filing vs. searching, it's an outdated habit from a time when email volumes were lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either a message is important enough for a major interruption - a pop-up window with a beep, for instance - or it's OK to let it sit for a while. The unread status alone is a poor substitute for "important", and we should move past it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>gmail</category><category>mail.app</category><category>quiet</category><category>thunderbird-3</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/unread-counts/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 17:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Let's talk some more email philosophy. An email client should help you quickly get through new email</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/lets-talk-some-more-email-philosophy-an-email-client-should-help-you-quickly-get-through-new-email/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's talk some more email philosophy. An email client should help you quickly get through new emails, on your schedule, and turn them into whatever you need them to be once you've read them. Then it should shut up until you call it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I'll point at &lt;a href="http://inboxzero.com/"&gt;Merlin Mann&lt;/a&gt; as my original inspiration, and if you want to hear more about the reasons behind this line of thought, go listen to his recent podcast appearances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further - I'm against unread counts, against new-mail sounds, against pop-up notification of new mail. I can't think of a job you could have where there's a good reason you should be interrupted by an email client for every new message. Sure, some things are important and ought to interrupt you - but there are a host of better technologies for urgent communication - IM, SMS, Phone calls, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm for search, against filing. If you're shuffling email into folders, part of what you're doing is building an index. Computers know how to index text, and they can do it faster and more completely than you can, so stop wasting your time - especially if you're just filing it according to data that's already in the message, like sender or date. If your filing system is adding some information to each message, then a client should just let you add that info quickly and then index it for you. Not enough clients do this well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, like many people, I work at a big company that runs its own email infrastructure and won't be giving control to Google any time soon. This means that while GMail is an interesting case study and a useful option for personal email, I need to use another client for most of my email. That's why mikechecksmail is about desktop mail clients. I use a Mac, and so it's about Mac desktop mail clients. That said, I won't ignore other systems - good ideas are good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>filing</category><category>gmail</category><category>inbox-zero</category><category>minimalism</category><category>notification</category><category>philosophy</category><category>quiet</category><category>search</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/03/lets-talk-some-more-email-philosophy-an-email-client-should-help-you-quickly-get-through-new-email/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>