<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (scripts)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 08:30:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>go juggle — an attention callback</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes progress on a project for me consists of a few short bursts of activity in between stretches of waiting for some long-running thing to complete so I can figure out what I need to do with it next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I always have more than one project going, I don't actually wait much. I just switch workspaces and try to make progress on the next thing. If I can't make progress on anything immediate, I'll end up checking email or looking up something for a side project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of multitasking is inefficient, but inevitable when I might have to wait for 20 minutes or more for a compute job or a compile to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this approach is that the things I'm waiting for often finish while I'm off doing something else, and if I get too involved, the low-priority research or emails will eat up my day while the high-priority work sits waiting for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've attacked this problem in the past when using OS X with &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/gr"&gt;growl&lt;/a&gt;, but I can't call growlnotify from remote systems. However, I just found &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/dzen"&gt;dzen&lt;/a&gt; for X Windows, a lightweight notification display utility that compiles easily on every system I've tried, and works remotely with ssh X forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a simple script called &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt;, which just executes its arguments and runs &lt;code&gt;dzen&lt;/code&gt; when it's done. Now I type (for example) &lt;code&gt;go make&lt;/code&gt; and I can switch over to something else, confident that I'll see a big popup window letting me know when I can get back to working on my highest priority project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's basically the entire &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="codehilitetable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2
3
4
5&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;#!/bin/ksh&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt; completed on &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;hostname&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="se"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
 | dzen2 -p -h 64 -bg darkblue
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's simple but it's working great for me. I've tried some improvements like randomizing window placement to avoid overlapping notifications, but the simple version above really does all I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a couple of details. zsh always seems to want to spell-check 'go', so I really named it '~/bin/executeAndNotify.sh' and just aliased 'go' to that.
Also, I've found it can mess with shell quoting as is, so sometimes I have to do &lt;code&gt;'somecommand ; go echo done'&lt;/code&gt;. If someone has a tip on getting the quoting right in the script, I'd love to hear it. The problem crops up when you try something like 'go make CC="cc -g"' - the quotes don't make it through.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>X Windows</category><category>computers</category><category>productivity</category><category>script utility productivity</category><category>scripts</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 02:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Twitter Stats in SVG using gnuplot</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/01/twitter-stats-in-svg-using-gnuplot/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/dacort"&gt;Damon Cortesi&lt;/a&gt; just shared a handy script for grabbing your tweets and compiling some stats about when you post to twitter and who you reply to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His script generates a list of numbers and included a Numbers template to paste them into. Since I don't have Numbers, I've modified &lt;a href="http://dcortesi.com/2007/12/27/twitter-stats/"&gt;his script&lt;/a&gt; to write a file that can be read by &lt;a href="http://gnuplot.info"&gt;gnuplot&lt;/a&gt;, and wrote a basic gnuplot script to output an SVG file version of the stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was at it, I changed it so it no longer counts "@someone" separately from "@someone:".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both scripts are right here - &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/twitter/gnuplot_twitterstats.tgz"&gt;gnuplot_twitterstats.tgz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses gnuplot 4.2, which you can get on OS X with &lt;a href="http://www.macports.org/"&gt;macports&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;code&gt;port install gnuplot +no_x11'&lt;/code&gt;. (Or it's a pretty easy build on its own, see the &lt;a href="http://gnuplot.sourceforge.net/download.html"&gt;gnuplot download page&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my stats:
Sorry, it looks like your browser doesn't support SVG. You're really not missing much.
&lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/twitter/2007stats.svg"&gt;Click here for a full-screen version.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>scripts</category><category>web</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/01/twitter-stats-in-svg-using-gnuplot/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2008 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A script for text placeholders in VoodooPad</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/03/a-script-for-text-placeholders-in-voodoopad/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I wrote about my &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/?p=39"&gt;new page template for VoodooPad&lt;/a&gt;. I still use something like it - I like the uniform look and the built-in navigation starters I get in every page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got tired of all the clicking around it took to fill in the navigation every time I put in a new page, so I decided to write a script to mimic XCode's "Select Next Placeholder" command. In XCode, if you use code completion, you might get something like this:
&lt;code&gt;[dict setObject:&amp;lt;# (id) anObject #&amp;gt; forKey:&amp;lt;# (id)key #&amp;gt;]&lt;/code&gt; Then pressing Control-/ cycles the selection through those placeholders so you can replace them with whatever you want quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's really handy for code, and it's great for VoodooPad templates too. I wrote the script as a Python script plugin for VoodooPad, and it maps Command-/ to select the next placeholder, wrapping the search at the end just like XCode does. Now my new page template in VoodooPad has a few placeholders in it, and I have a lot fewer pages with default template text sitting in there making me look lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download it &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/Select-Next-Placeholder.py"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (Note, it needs the &lt;a href="http://flyingmeat.com/fs/flystashweb.cgi/40de692c-e33c-01d9-12a1-c0cbe4c4d9e7"&gt;VoodooPad Python Plugin Enabler&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>VoodooPad</category><category>mac</category><category>scripts</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/03/a-script-for-text-placeholders-in-voodoopad/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>