<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (script utility productivity)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/script-utility-productivity.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>go juggle — an attention callback</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes progress on a project for me consists of a few short bursts of activity in between stretches of waiting for some long-running thing to complete so I can figure out what I need to do with it next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I always have more than one project going, I don't actually wait much. I just switch workspaces and try to make progress on the next thing. If I can't make progress on anything immediate, I'll end up checking email or looking up something for a side project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of multitasking is inefficient, but inevitable when I might have to wait for 20 minutes or more for a compute job or a compile to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this approach is that the things I'm waiting for often finish while I'm off doing something else, and if I get too involved, the low-priority research or emails will eat up my day while the high-priority work sits waiting for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've attacked this problem in the past when using OS X with &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/gr"&gt;growl&lt;/a&gt;, but I can't call growlnotify from remote systems. However, I just found &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/dzen"&gt;dzen&lt;/a&gt; for X Windows, a lightweight notification display utility that compiles easily on every system I've tried, and works remotely with ssh X forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a simple script called &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt;, which just executes its arguments and runs &lt;code&gt;dzen&lt;/code&gt; when it's done. Now I type (for example) &lt;code&gt;go make&lt;/code&gt; and I can switch over to something else, confident that I'll see a big popup window letting me know when I can get back to working on my highest priority project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's basically the entire &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="codehilitetable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2
3
4
5&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;#!/bin/ksh&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt; completed on &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;hostname&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="se"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; dzen2 -p -h &lt;span class="m"&gt;64&lt;/span&gt; -bg darkblue
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's simple but it's working great for me. I've tried some improvements like randomizing window placement to avoid overlapping notifications, but the simple version above really does all I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a couple of details. zsh always seems to want to spell-check 'go', so I really named it '~/bin/executeAndNotify.sh' and just aliased 'go' to that.
Also, I've found it can mess with shell quoting as is, so sometimes I have to do &lt;code&gt;'somecommand ; go echo done'&lt;/code&gt;. If someone has a tip on getting the quoting right in the script, I'd love to hear it. The problem crops up when you try something like 'go make CC="cc -g"' - the quotes don't make it through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>computers</category><category>productivity</category><category>script utility productivity</category><category>scripts</category><category>X Windows</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2008/08/go-juggle-an-attention-callback/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 02:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>