<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (tips)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 08:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Links for September 27th through October 14th</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/10/links-for-september-27th-through-october-14th/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My shared links for September 27th through October 14th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/pyprocessing/"&gt;pyprocessing - A Processing-like environment for doing graphics with Python - Google Project Hosting&lt;/a&gt; - processing in python. uses pyglet. installs very easily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ece.ucdavis.edu/~jowens/commonerrors.html"&gt;Common Errors in Technical Writing&lt;/a&gt; - A list of common errors and peeves in technical writing. Very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://soft.vub.ac.be/~smarr/renaissance/"&gt;Renaissance: Harness Emergence to Avoid the Concurrency Trap&lt;/a&gt; - Languages for non-deterministic computing, and a manycore squeak VM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://waxy.org/2011/09/geeks_guide_to_portland_2011/"&gt;Geek's Guide to Portland 2011 - Waxy.org&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://candyspotting.com/index.php/cards/holiday/houndstooth-snowsuit.html"&gt;Candyspotting - Houndstooth Snowsuit Card - Holiday&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.llvm.org/2011/09/greedy-register-allocation-in-llvm-30.html"&gt;LLVM Project Blog: Greedy Register Allocation in LLVM 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ergo.human.cornell.edu/CUESitStand.html"&gt;CUergo: Sitting and Standing&lt;/a&gt; - Short version: sit at your desk, but get up every 20 minutes and move around for 2 minutes. That's probably a good time to focus your eyes somewhere else too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pandas.sourceforge.net/"&gt;pandas: powerful Python data analysis toolkit -- pandas v0.4.0 documentation&lt;/a&gt; - python package for labeled multidimensional data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>bibtex</category><category>christmas</category><category>concurrency</category><category>exascale</category><category>food</category><category>gift</category><category>graphics</category><category>greeting-card</category><category>guide</category><category>languages</category><category>latex</category><category>links</category><category>ly</category><category>pinboard-links</category><category>portland</category><category>processing</category><category>programming</category><category>python</category><category>research</category><category>sly</category><category>smalltalk</category><category>squeak</category><category>tips</category><category>travel</category><category>visualization</category><category>winter</category><category>writing</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/10/links-for-september-27th-through-october-14th/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 23:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>VoodooPad, OmniFocus and Terminal Integration Wish List</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/07/voodoopad-omnifocus-and-terminal-integration-wish-list/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some features I want but I'll never have time to write the scripts for VoodooPad to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use VP mostly as a running log of notes, shell commands and todos. I also use OmniFocus for task tracking, but sometimes it's easier to just start typing in VP and work out the tasks later. So I often end up with VP pages that have a bunch of todos mixed in with project headers and miscellaneous notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking some integration would be nice. I want an &lt;del&gt;&lt;a href="http://orgmode.org/"&gt;emacs org-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (update: I meant &lt;a href="http://www.isi.edu/~johnh/SOFTWARE/NOTES_MODE/"&gt;notes-mode&lt;/a&gt;) style "new day" script that creates a new page for the day and does the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adds a link to the new page to the previous note page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moves any pending todos (I mark them as lines starting with a &amp;lt;# todo #&amp;gt; placeholder so I can jump to them) off yesterday's page and into OmniFocus &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;starts a new header (line starting with #, in bold) in the new page for every header that had leftover todos. These headers usually correspond to projects in OmniFocus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adds new headers and todo lines for any tasks that are due today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to have VP autocomplete project names from OmniFocus when I start a header line. Then add a link next to the new header pointing to the last page containing that header. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd also like to have OmniFocus update the VP document when I check off a task in OF - I want to use VP as a log, so I can track down when I did something. Maybe projects should all have their own VP pages, that are kind of an auto-updated index of progress on the tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'd also be nice if when I edited a todo line in VP, it could update OF. I guess I want VP to be an supplemental synchronized view onto my OF tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Terminal: I do a lot of copying and pasting shell commands into VP so I can remember things like important paths, or the exact configure settings I used to build something two years ago. This is really useful, but it'd be nice if it was easier to do without leaving the terminal. Ideally I could just prefix a command with something like '@' to add it to the current page in VP (or '@pagename#headername' to get fancy). You could get this with a script named '@' - on your local machine. But it also has to work when you're working remotely, so it will get a little more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally - this is something I wanted to try doing with an InputManager before that mechanism went away: I'd like CamelCase links in every text field on the system (probably with some exceptions) to automatically link to VP pages. But it sounds like the days of modifying system-wide behavior on Macs are history, so I'll probably never get this. Who knows, maybe it would've been a disaster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always thought the path to improvement in work computing was more and deeper integration between 3rd-party apps, as well as more system functionality that's usable by all those apps, but it looks to me* like in OS X we're only getting the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* - since 10.7 is about to come out, it might be worth pointing out that I have no special advance developer info. I haven't even been a dev program member for a few years now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>productivity</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2011/07/voodoopad-omnifocus-and-terminal-integration-wish-list/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 21:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A script for text placeholders in VoodooPad</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/03/a-script-for-text-placeholders-in-voodoopad/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I wrote about my &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/wp/?p=39"&gt;new page template for VoodooPad&lt;/a&gt;. I still use something like it - I like the uniform look and the built-in navigation starters I get in every page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got tired of all the clicking around it took to fill in the navigation every time I put in a new page, so I decided to write a script to mimic XCode's "Select Next Placeholder" command. In XCode, if you use code completion, you might get something like this:
&lt;code&gt;[dict setObject:&amp;lt;# (id) anObject #&amp;gt; forKey:&amp;lt;# (id)key #&amp;gt;]&lt;/code&gt; Then pressing Control-/ cycles the selection through those placeholders so you can replace them with whatever you want quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's really handy for code, and it's great for VoodooPad templates too. I wrote the script as a Python script plugin for VoodooPad, and it maps Command-/ to select the next placeholder, wrapping the search at the end just like XCode does. Now my new page template in VoodooPad has a few placeholders in it, and I have a lot fewer pages with default template text sitting in there making me look lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download it &lt;a href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/Select-Next-Placeholder.py"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (Note, it needs the &lt;a href="http://flyingmeat.com/fs/flystashweb.cgi/40de692c-e33c-01d9-12a1-c0cbe4c4d9e7"&gt;VoodooPad Python Plugin Enabler&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>VoodooPad</category><category>mac</category><category>scripts</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/03/a-script-for-text-placeholders-in-voodoopad/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Linking the OS X Clipboard and XTerm's selection</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/linking-the-os-x-clipboard-and-xterms-selection/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;If you only use X11 for XTerm, it might seem like the handling of the clipboard in Apple's X11.app is broken. You can select text and paste it with a click of the middle mouse button (opt-click on my Powerbook), and that works when pasting into other X apps, but it doesn't change the Mac clipboard at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? Is X11.app just ignoring the X clipboard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No - X11.app &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; synchronize the two clipboards. The problem is that the selection pasting in XTerm is using a completely different buffer. There's a full and clear explanation, with some interesting details about (X)Emacs' behavior, at &lt;a href="http://www.jwz.org/doc/x-cut-and-paste.html"&gt;jwz.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, like me, you only use X11 for Emacs and XTerm, you might want to link the selection in XTerm to the X clipboard, so X11.app will then sync that with the system clipboard and you can select in XTerm and paste with Cmd-V in say, Mail.app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll tell you how in a sec, but first the caveat - I said if you only use X11 for Emacs and XTerm because what we're going to do is make setting the XTerm selection always overwrite the clipboard contents. If you use X apps that use the X clipboard, sometimes you don't want that. So beware. If you use Emacs, it just pushes onto the kill ring, so you're good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, now that that's over, add these lines to your ~/.Xdefaults:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;XTerm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;VT100.Translations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;#override&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;BtnUp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;select&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;-end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;CLIPBOARD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;PRIMARY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;Btn2Down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;insert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;-selection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;PRIMARY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Note that the backslashes at the end of the lines are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: The first version of this post didn't include the Btn2Down action. Without that, the original paste behavior goes away - the man page doesn't really explain the "#override" keyword, so I'm not sure why.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>X Windows</category><category>mac</category><category>tips</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/linking-the-os-x-clipboard-and-xterms-selection/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 02:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>