<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (wave)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 08:30:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mozilla Raindrop</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/mozilla-raindrop/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I noticed the &lt;a href="http://labs.mozilla.com/raindrop/"&gt;Mozilla Raindrop&lt;/a&gt; project. It's an interesting project in Mozilla Labs by the Thunderbird team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's trying to rethink how messaging (in general, not just email) should work - using open web technologies. On the surface it sounds like Google Wave, but I'd say it's aiming a little lower - trying to take existing protocols and build software that handles them all together in a better way. I also think it's a better approach than Wave, focusing on designing a single artifact that people will want to use instead of a framework technology demo, which is what Wave always seemed to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like it's not intended to be a native desktop (or mobile) client - they mention running it on servers, and it depends on Python and CouchDB, which would preclude it running on the iPhone OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like about it is the way they're trying to use a classification of emails - obviously, not all mails are equal. They fall somewhere in a range between spam and important personal (or work) messages. A big class is "bulk" mail - mail that's useful but not necessarily of a conversation involving you. Mailing lists, promotional mails you've asked for, facebook/twitter notifications might all fall into this category, and it's a great idea for a mailer to do something different with them. At the least, it should let you ignore them if you're just trying to do a quick processing pass of new mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://blogs.mozillamessaging.com/raindropdesign/"&gt;Raindrop design blog&lt;/a&gt; has some good posts (with plenty of screenshots) outlining their current approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>bulk-mail</category><category>mozilla</category><category>mozilla-labs</category><category>raindrop</category><category>wave</category><category>webmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/mozilla-raindrop/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Email Death Link Dump</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/10/email-death-link-dump/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent Wall Street Journal article &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203803904574431151489408372.html"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; (pay link) the rise of alternatives to email. The article itself is balanced and mentions that new ways of communicating are likely to just add to how much time we spend with this stuff, not replace email and cure its problems. Whether that's good or bad depends on what you're communicating, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article inspired a number of posts about the death of email, misunderstanding the article, but providing some interesting info. Here's a few of them. Both &lt;a href="http://www.emailserviceguide.com/2009/10/the-end-of-email-predicted-wrong-as-usual/"&gt;The End of Email Predicted, Wrong as Usual&lt;/a&gt;, from emailserviceguide.com, and &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/blog/kit-eaton/technomix/email-phenomenon-its-last-legs"&gt;Why Twitter and Facebook Will Never Kill E-mail&lt;/a&gt; from the technomix blog at FastCompany.com make some good points about some uses for which emerging 'cloud' services are just not as good as email. They mostly focus on business, which makes sense. You probably don't want another company between you and your customers or partners. Imagine if you could only hold meetings at Starbucks - hit or miss, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rackspace.com's email hosting blog gives us some data in a post entitled &lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com/email_hosting/blog/2009/09/is-email-dead/"&gt;"Is Email dead?"&lt;/a&gt; short answer -  no. It's getting bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And surprisingly, there were a good number of lucid and interesting comments in the &lt;a href="http://tech.slashdot.org/story/09/10/14/016257/Yet-Another-Premature-Declaration-of-Emails-Death?art_pos=1"&gt;slashdot thread&lt;/a&gt; about the article. Provided you filter out comments with a score of 3 and lower...&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>email</category><category>facebook</category><category>twitter</category><category>wave</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2009/10/email-death-link-dump/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 20:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>