<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>michael-mccracken.net (webmail)</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://michael-mccracken.net/categories/webmail.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 19:12:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>I ran across this video in my bookmarks - this looks like the result of Yahoo acquiring [Xoopit](htt</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/i-ran-across-this-video-in-my-bookmarks-this-looks-like-the-result-of-yahoo-acquiring-xoopithttpxoopitcom-it-looks-like-theyve-got-a-platform-for-building-applications-that-users-can-add-into-their-we/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran across this video in my bookmarks - this looks like the result of Yahoo acquiring &lt;a href="http://xoopit.com/"&gt;Xoopit&lt;/a&gt;. It looks like they've got a platform for building "applications" that users can add into their webmail client. (Here's the &lt;a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/mailapplications/"&gt;developer info&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a little like Facebook's games and other apps, and I'd be surprised if that's not what they're competing with. However, it's another good idea from web apps that would work in desktop apps too - why not allow other applications to easily see and work with the data you've got in mail? This kind of app could either be a plug-in add-on to the mail client or a separate app that just accesses the mail data directly. Supporting both would be great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>apps</category><category>plugins</category><category>webmail</category><category>yahoo-mail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/05/i-ran-across-this-video-in-my-bookmarks-this-looks-like-the-result-of-yahoo-acquiring-xoopithttpxoopitcom-it-looks-like-theyve-got-a-platform-for-building-applications-that-users-can-add-into-their-we/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 14:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mozilla Raindrop</title><link>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/mozilla-raindrop/</link><dc:creator>Michael McCracken</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I noticed the &lt;a href="http://labs.mozilla.com/raindrop/"&gt;Mozilla Raindrop&lt;/a&gt; project. It's an interesting project in Mozilla Labs by the Thunderbird team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's trying to rethink how messaging (in general, not just email) should work - using open web technologies. On the surface it sounds like Google Wave, but I'd say it's aiming a little lower - trying to take existing protocols and build software that handles them all together in a better way. I also think it's a better approach than Wave, focusing on designing a single artifact that people will want to use instead of a framework technology demo, which is what Wave always seemed to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like it's not intended to be a native desktop (or mobile) client - they mention running it on servers, and it depends on Python and CouchDB, which would preclude it running on the iPhone OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I like about it is the way they're trying to use a classification of emails - obviously, not all mails are equal. They fall somewhere in a range between spam and important personal (or work) messages. A big class is "bulk" mail - mail that's useful but not necessarily of a conversation involving you. Mailing lists, promotional mails you've asked for, facebook/twitter notifications might all fall into this category, and it's a great idea for a mailer to do something different with them. At the least, it should let you ignore them if you're just trying to do a quick processing pass of new mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://blogs.mozillamessaging.com/raindropdesign/"&gt;Raindrop design blog&lt;/a&gt; has some good posts (with plenty of screenshots) outlining their current approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bulk-mail</category><category>mozilla</category><category>mozilla-labs</category><category>raindrop</category><category>wave</category><category>webmail</category><guid>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/04/mozilla-raindrop/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>