<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reviews | michael-mccracken.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-15T09:01:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael McCracken]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TaskPaper adds just enough to stick]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2007/11/01/taskpaper-adds-just-enough-to-stick/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-01T05:47:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2007/11/01/taskpaper-adds-just-enough-to-stick</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My favorite apps, the ones that slip easily into everyday use and stick there, just start with plain text and add some extra sauce. <a href="http://voodoopad.com">VoodooPad</a> is a great example, and Hog Bay Software's new app <a href="http://hogbaysoftware.com/products/taskpaper">TaskPaper</a> is, too.</p>

<p>I've used both <a href="http://kinkless.com/kgtd">kgtd</a> and <a href="http://bargiel.home.pl/iGTD/">iGTD</a>, and played around with a few others. I came closest to sticking with a system using kgtd, but switched to iGTD because manually syncing kgtd got old.</p>

<p>All the extra <em>stuff</em> in iGTD was appealing, but I left tasks in the inbox for weeks, and never reviewed much of my vast forest of projects. I eventually fell back into tending short lists in Stickies, with titles like "<strong>NOW</strong>:" and "<strong>BY TUESDAY!</strong>:".</p>

<p>When I moved those Stickies lists into TaskPaper, all I had to do was copy and paste - it uses the same format I do when I get lazy, and that has to be a good sign. I haven't found a reason to jot a note somewhere else yet.</p>

<p>Moving tasks from iGTD was more sobering. Half those "next actions" had been done for weeks, and the other half were clearly scheduled for next Neversday. As Merlin Mann pointed out, <a href="http://www.43folders.com/2007/06/04/getting-ready-for-omnifocus">switching apps is a good excuse for a real review</a>.</p>

<p>TaskPaper adds automatic formatting, tabs, search, and a bit of hyperlinking to plain text.
Tasks are lines that start with a dash, and can be tagged by starting any word with an at-sign. Clicking a tag starts a search for that tag. I use them in a couple of ways - as contexts, and for scheduling. They can really be anything that makes sense as a visible search keyword.</p>

<p>I have been keeping a few tabs open - one to edit tasks, and a couple others with live searches to look at what's on my plate. When I want to schedule something, I'll tag it as @now or @tomorrow - I have those two as open tabs, and as I work I keep the @now tab open.
Other tabs come and go to look at contexts, like @email or @errand.</p>

<p>I like that the tags can be part of the sentence, so I don't have to tab through a bunch of controls to set tags - I just write something like '@email Bob @home'... easy.</p>

<p>I also set up an inbox project (by typing "Inbox:", naturally) to collect notes quickly, and that's worked pretty well so far.</p>

<p>As with any 1.0, there's some room for improvement. It's not very scriptable, but it is plain text, so it could be worked around. Quicksilver integration was important with both kGTD and iGTD, and I'm not sure yet if I'll really miss that here.
It can clean up tasks marked as done into an "Archive" project, but doesn't yet note when they were finished, if that kind of thing matters to you. Finally, I'm not sure what the best way to sync with other devices would be, but there is a <a href="http://hogbaysoftware.com/products/taskpaper_web">web interface</a> in development - maybe that would be a good iPhone option.</p>

<p>TaskPaper is a solid, clear, and nicely minimalist app. Over the week I've been using it, it has made keeping to-dos in one place too easy to avoid, and added just enough functionality to sort through them without being distracting.</p>

<p>Note:
When I downloaded the 1.0 release, I found a conflict with TextExtras and wrote a <a href="http://hogbaysoftware.com/forums/taskpaper/topics/294_Archive_bug_in_1_22_">bug report</a>. In reply, Jesse sent me a complimentary license. Nice guy. I was going to write about it anyway, but I thought I should mention that I got it for free, as a surprise.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FlexTime 1.0 Launches]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/08/17/flextime-10-launches/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-17T08:25:24-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/08/17/flextime-10-launches</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been using Red Sweater software's <a href="http://www.red-sweater.com/flextime/">FlexTime</a> for a while now, and Daniel just announced version 1.0.</p>

<p>FlexTime is a repeating-timer program that is great for either set routines or one-off reminders. (It also has a pretty great name, don't you think?)</p>

<p>It's a solid program that you can use for a number of things. It fills an important niche I care about - helping you deal with your #1 work tool also being your #1 toy.</p>

<p>I use it to do a version of the <a href="http://www.43folders.com/2005/10/11/procrastination-hack-1025/">"(10+2)*"</a> procrastination hack that helps me get on track doing the things I need to do. It works really well, and I love that it lets me pause a routine if work is going really well.</p>

<p>Perhaps the best endorsement I can give it is that even though it does what I need, I am constantly thinking of things I wish it did and ways to improve. Now that I've mentioned that, I guess I'll have to schedule some time to send my list over to Daniel...</p>

<p>Well, time's up - back to work!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Screen Focus]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/04/19/full-screen-focus/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-19T10:38:08-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/04/19/full-screen-focus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I visit <a href="http://www.43folders.com">43Folders</a> only about once a week now - I couldn't deal with the cognitive dissonance implied by procrastinating by visiting a site about how to be more efficient and avoid procrastination.</p>

<p>I was really glad yesterday to see Merlin's post about <a href="http://www.43folders.com/2006/04/17/fsm2-electric-boogaloo/">faking full screen mode</a> with a trio of useful apps. I had tried <a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/16640">Menushade</a> before, and didn't really see the point - the menu bar doesn't bug me - but in combination with the other two that Merlin recommends, <a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/15844">Spirited Away</a> and <a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/15426">BackDrop</a>, his scheme is a really great way to turn your computer into a tool for focus and not diversion.</p>

<p>At first I thought I wanted a faster auto-hide than the default 60 seconds, but after a bit of time with the delay set to zero and then a less disconcerting 10 seconds, I decided that it was confusing to lose context that quickly, so the default's been working well for me. Also, it makes diversions painfully obvious when your work-related windows blink away and you're sitting staring at ESPN. It immediately begs the question: "You've already wasted one minute - is this that important?"</p>

<p>I was also reluctant to hide the dock, but I tried it, and now I'm never going back. I have <a href="http://c-command.com/spamsieve">SpamSieve</a> and <a href="http://growl.info">Growl</a> to point out important emails (checking once an hour), and for the rest of the time, my numerous diversions are better off out of sight, out of mind.</p>

<p>Another tactic I've started using is a dedicated browser app for Gmail. Just because I need to look at my mail doesn't mean I need to spend some time checking hockey scores - so I built a separate browser that only loads Gmail, and that temptation is gone. I'll probably post more about that sometime later, but for now, I need to get back to work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ingredients: prunes, salt.]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/04/01/ingredients-prunes-salt/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-01T19:13:39-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/04/01/ingredients-prunes-salt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you're ever at the liquor store down the block and see a tempting new combination of previously unconnected flavors, and you feel a sudden urge, a <em>tug</em>, to buy that bag of Salted Prune Saladitos and rush home, eager to shut the door behind you and experience something alien and tasty in private, stop. Just pay for your diet coke, leave a penny, and walk home a fortunate, humbler man.</p>

<p><img src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/Saladitos.jpg" alt="Saladitos." /></p>

<p>Prune Saladitos: fit for a king with a powerful jaw.</p>

<p>The one Saladito I tried was probably harder than anything else I've been told was food, and certainly the saltiest thing I've ever tasted, including <em>salt</em>. It was like biting a really big, wrinkly pistachio, shell and all. A two-hour soak in warm water did little to soften the nugget, and now this bag sits in my kitchen, awaiting fate. Maybe someday I'll try a fresh one.</p>

<p>You're wondering where else you can read about these formidable treats on the internet. I've already done the background for you, and I recommend <a href="http://www.teensupreme.org/news_120403.html">learning about diversity</a> with lemons and saladitos.</p>

<p>To be fair, King Henry does make a delicious trail mix.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buying my TV from the iTunes Music Store?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/04/01/buying-my-tv-from-the-itunes-music-store/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-01T18:23:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/04/01/buying-my-tv-from-the-itunes-music-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don't have cable TV service anymore. Now I have NetFlix and books instead, and so far that's working out OK for me - but as much as I can't handle 300 channels, I would really like to be able to pick a few programs to watch.</p>

<p>Thus, I'm cautiously optimistic about getting my TV over the internet. I think it could be cost-effective for me - cable bills can be pretty expensive, so even though TV <em>seems</em> cheap, consider how much crap you have to watch to get the price per show lower than $2. Is it worth it? Suppose I watch two games a week and three shows each week. At current iTunes rates, that's about $10 a week or $40 a month, assuming I don't get discounts for season passes, or screwed on sporting events. That's not bad.</p>

<p>But is it a comparable product? I watched an episode of <a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewVideo?id=136742502&amp;p;=136546559&amp;s;=143441">Scrubs</a> today, and I'd have to say yes and no.</p>

<p>Buying it went smoothly, not having to watch commercials <em>is</em> pretty great, and I assume I can send the audio to my Airport Express, right? However, you wait for it to download the whole thing first, the resolution is low, pausing and scanning through the video sometimes hangs briefly, and I'm not sold on having the video play in a separate window - it seems like a major afterthought. I'm really curious why iTunes is a worse video player than the Quicktime Player for the same exact file.</p>

<p>The file's 104MB, and I'm not likely to watch it over and over again - what I am likely to do is keep it around because I'd feel guilty trashing something I'd paid for. I'd be much happier if I knew I could re-download these shows in the future, so I'm not saddled with a massive file if I don't need it around.</p>

<p>What's more, I remember pretty clearly sitting in the audience for Steve Jobs' keynote in <em>2004</em>, and watching him demo super-fast, live, streaming playback and scrubbing around H.264 high definition content. It was pretty impressive. Two years later, where's the HD content? HD would really sell video on the internet - not many people have HDTVs, but lots of people these days have a monitor that can display at least 720p (1280x720), and once you watch sports in HD, you're hooked.</p>

<p>So - I say, bring on the laptop HD revolution. Bring on live HD sports via iTunes. Let me stream it and re-stream it. Let <em>me</em> decide what to pay for - I don't want to have my cash go to subsidize Elimidate, ever again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
