<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: me | michael-mccracken.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/categories/me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T08:51:19-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael McCracken]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tinkering in the Sideshow]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/02/tinkering-in-the-sideshow/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-02T18:31:06-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2010/02/tinkering-in-the-sideshow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, <a href="http://al3x.net/2010/01/28/ipad.html">Alex Payne</a> and <a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset">Mark Pilgrim</a> both made some heartfelt arguments explaining why they think the fact that Apple's vision of the computing future as a relatively closed appliance is depressing. I agree, and I want to explain exactly why, now that I think I've figured it out.</p>

<p>Each post got plenty of responses. Dissenters have a wide variety of reasons for why it's no big deal, ranging from "tomorrows tinkerers will just play with different technology, like <a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset#comment-13600">bio-mecha</a>" (fascinating!), to a lot of people saying, essentially, "Just don't buy the appliance if you want a computer" (obvious!).</p>

<p>Others have made a solid point that the iPad is the next big computing paradigm. Steven Frank calls it a <a href="http://stevenf.tumblr.com/post/359224392/i-need-to-talk-to-you-about-computers-ive-been">"New World"</a> device. I can't help but agree, and of course powerful devices that empower instead of confuse the user are a good thing. Replacing most of the world's overcomplicated, fussy laptops with focused and reliable devices is a good thing.</p>

<p>Of course, general purpose, hackable computers are not really going away, not soon. Even if everyone uses an iPad for personal stuff and a Chrome OS netbook to access private cloud services for business work, there will still be a need for workstations, and I hope the people building complete personal systems out of Free Software don't give up.</p>

<p>However, in a response to comments on his post, <a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2010/01/29/tinkerers-sunset#comment-13616">Mark Pilgrim made a gloomy prediction</a>: "People haven’t figured it out yet, but Mac OS X is on its last legs. By 2015, Apple will make appliances and developer add-ons. Not general purpose computing devices."</p>

<p>If you ask me, this is the real problem.</p>

<p>The problem is that hackable computers <em>that I want to use</em> could very well be fading out. Maybe Mark's overstating things, but I would not be surprised to see the Mac, and OS X, as a relatively low priority for Apple in the near future. Design and development effort and creativity will naturally go increasingly toward the more profitable platform - the one making computing finally pleasant for the normal person.</p>

<p>I'm worried that this will happen for third-party developers too. <a href="http://violasong.com/2010/02/my-worst-ipad-fears">I'm not the only one.</a> Back in 2002, Brent Simmons described developing user code for the Mac as <a href="http://inessential.com/2002/09/19/why_i_develop_for_mac_os_x">"the show"</a>. Is there any doubt that Apple's mobile OS is "the show" now?</p>

<p>Where does that leave the rest of us who still have to or want to use a more powerful platform?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share how you use BibDesk]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/share-how-you-use-bibdesk/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-22T04:14:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/02/share-how-you-use-bibdesk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use <a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/">BibDesk</a>, I want to hear how you use it - what features you use most, and how you have it set up.</p>

<p>I've added a page to the BibDesk wiki to share <a href="http://bibdesk.sourceforge.net/wiki/index.php/User_Screenshots">User Screenshots</a> - add a section there about what you do with BibDesk, and share your experiences. I added my own thoughts already, to get things started.</p>

<p>(Note, image uploading on the wiki is broken right now, I'll fix it as soon as I can and update this post. Please add text anyway!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leopard Tech Talk, Jan 19: LA]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/leopard-tech-talk-jan-19-la/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-09T07:10:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/01/leopard-tech-talk-jan-19-la</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I couldn't make it to WWDC last year, I'm not at Macworld this week, but I will be making it up to LA on the 19th for the <a href="http://developer.apple.com/events/techtalks/northamerica.html">Leopard Tech Talk</a>, to catch up. I'll probably be there the day before, owing to traffic and an inability to wake up early.</p>

<p>If any area mac devs are meeting up around then, drop me a note.</p>

<p>I wonder if we'll know anything by then about developing for the iPhone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GTD Habits]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/11/gtd-habits/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-15T04:07:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/11/gtd-habits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After years of being aware of <a href="http://davidco.com/">David Allen's</a> GTD system through <a href="http://www.43folders.com/topics/gtd">43 Folders</a> and other sites, I took the dive about a month ago and dumped all my various to-do lists and project ideas into <a href="http://kinkless.com">Kinkless GTD</a>. I had tried to keep reminders and actions in a variety of other systems, including emacs <a href="http://staff.science.uva.nl/~dominik/Tools/org/">org-mode</a> and <a href="http://voodoopad.com">VoodooPad</a>, which I use extensively for notes.</p>

<p>I never kept up a system for very long, and I believe the contexts were the key problem - having to look at tasks with different contexts in the same list is daunting - I end up not writing things down to avoid a frightening list, and keeping multiple lists around is difficult in every system I tried, until I tried Kinkless. Organizing by context gives a great feeling of confidence when I ignore huge lists that I just can't do right now. Knowing what you can't do makes getting the rest started much easier.</p>

<p>I'm not going to write a big series of posts describing my system or anything - I might have something to say about contexts later, but I would like to say that "vanilla" GTD can work for programmers, graduate students, etc - <em>without</em> major changes. Avoid the temptation to focus on your methods and just try using the simplest thing you can get away with. It'll probably work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supercomputing 2006 BOF: "Is 99% Utilization of a Supercomputer a Good Thing?"]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/10/supercomputing-2006-bof-is-99-utilization-of-a-supercomputer-a-good-thing/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-30T07:28:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/10/supercomputing-2006-bof-is-99-utilization-of-a-supercomputer-a-good-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those few readers who are interested in High Performance Computing and might be going to this year's <a href="http://sc06.supercomputing.org/">Supercomputing</a> conference in Tampa, my advisor Allan Snavely and Jeremy Kepner from Lincoln Labs are putting on a BOF with an intriguing subject: <a href="http://sc06.supercomputing.org/schedule/event_detail.php?evid=5193">"Is 99% Utilization of a Supercomputer a Good Thing?"</a></p>

<p>It'll be on Thursday Nov. 16th at 12:15PM.</p>

<p>As with all really interesting questions, this has a quick, easy answer that reveals your point of view. My immediate answer is "No", because of the productivity problems the focus on high utilization causes for many HPC users, mainly through the use of a batch queue. However, when considering the interests of everyone involved (including the people who have to evaluate how money is spent on these systems), the only responsible way to answer is "it depends".</p>

<p>It's an interesting topic that never fails to generate some controversy, and from what I can tell we'll have some diverse speakers at the BOF (including myself, discussing user surveys we've conducted as part of DARPA HPCS). It should be enlightening.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
