<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: grad-school | michael-mccracken.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/categories/grad-school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-09T00:37:19-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael McCracken]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Skim: Stop printing - Start Skimming.]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2007/04/02/announcing-skim-stop-printing-start-skimming/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-02T04:12:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2007/04/02/announcing-skim-stop-printing-start-skimming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you spend a lot of time reading articles and research papers that you get in PDF form, then you might be interested in the latest app from the folks who brought you <a href="http://bibdesk.sf.net">BibDesk</a>. If you already use BibDesk, then you certainly want to take a look.</p>

<p>Even though we keep our research papers stored on disk as PDF, all too often we print them out to read and write notes on. There's something missing in the experience of reading papers on a computer, but it doesn't have to be that way.</p>

<p><img src="http://skim-app.sourceforge.net/images/skimIcon.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Announcing <a href="http://skim-app.sf.net">Skim</a>. Skim is a PDF reading and note-taking app for Mac OS X that is designed to make reading research papers and manuals better. Just like in Preview, you can search, scan, and zoom through PDFs, but you also get some custom features for your workflow:</p>

<ul>
<li>Snapshots: if there's a graph on page two and the description continues to page three, just draw a box around the graph with the command key down and a snapshot window pops up with the graph, and you can keep on reading with the graph in view. For more fun, minimize that snapshot window - they stick around in their own dock in the document window.</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/skimSnapshot.png" alt="" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Tooltips: If a PDF has links, such as for citation references or indexes and section headings, you can click on them as usual to go to the destination, but there's more - hover the mouse over those links and Skim will show you a tooltip with the target of the link. No more losing your place to peek at a citation! For more fun, command-click on a link to pop up a snapshot window showing the link's destination.</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://michael-mccracken.net/2007/skimTooltip.png" alt="" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Presentation and Full-screen Modes: Full-screen reading is handy. So is showing a PDF as a presentation. But they're a little different. For instance, you might not want to show the table of contents in a presentation, but it's nice to see it when you're just reading by yourself. So Full-screen and Presentation are separate modes in Skim.</li>
</ul>


<p>There's plenty more - <a href="http://skim-app.sf.net">download it</a> and take a look, and join the <a href="http://skim-app.sf.net/mailingLists.html">mailing list</a> to discuss it. There's even a full help book in the first public beta release!</p>

<p>Many thanks to everyone who has worked on this app, and especially to Christiaan Hofman, who moved the app from a prototype to something really useful faster than I would have thought possible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomorrow's Professor Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/03/07/tomorrows-professor-blog/"/>
    <updated>2006-03-07T10:13:31-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/03/07/tomorrows-professor-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://ctl.stanford.edu/Tomprof/index.shtml">Tomorrow's Professor Mailing List</a>, a great resource for tips and info about what professors actually do (as opposed to what you learn in grad school), is now out in a weblog form, in case you'd rather read in an aggregator than a mail client: <a href="http://amps-tools.mit.edu/tomprofblog/">Tomorrow's Professor Blog</a></p>

<p>I'd recommend poking through the back issues - there's a lot of wisdom in there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing LENS]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/02/14/introducing-lens/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-14T12:29:10-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/02/14/introducing-lens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've just put up the website for my current project (to be part of my Ph.D. dissertation work): <a href="http://www.cse.ucsd.edu/~mmccrack/lens/">LENS</a>, a framework for program information manipulation that presents a uniform interface to selective user and automated queries about many types of program metrics, including success and diagnostic information about compiler optimizations and code generation.</p>

<p>I'm not sure how many readers of my weblog will be interested, but there's a link to a technical report on there if you want the gory details.</p>

<p>Feedback and questions are very welcome - the more opportunities I get to explain what I'm doing, the better I get at it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jorge Cham and "The Power of Procrastination"]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/02/08/jorge-cham-and-the-power-of-procrastination/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-08T13:26:31-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/02/08/jorge-cham-and-the-power-of-procrastination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just went to see Jorge Cham's talk <a href="http://www.phdcomics.com/speaking.htm">"The Power of Procrastination"</a> about grad school.
There were plenty of good grad-school jokes and a general feeling of relief that comes with being in a big room full of people who laugh at the same old chestnuts about how nobody ever really feels like they fit in and always feel guilty about whatever it is you spend your free time doing - you know, when you <em>should</em> be doing research!</p>

<p>If you get a chance to see his talk, go for it, even if you've read all the comics, it'll make you feel better. And if you haven't seen the comics, go <a href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/comics.php">read them all first</a>, then see the talk. Now I'm going to get back to work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's hot in CS]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/02/04/whats-hot-in-cs/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-04T17:02:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikemccracken.github.com/blog/2006/02/04/whats-hot-in-cs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, a group of graduating PhD students in our department met up to brief each other on what's new and hot in their respective fields, to remind each other of what's going on outside their respective specialties. The idea is that when interviewing for jobs, you have to hold up your end of a conversation with professors outside your specialty, and it helps to know a bit about their field.</p>

<p>To quote one professor in our department, "...there is a special circle
of hell reserved for grad students interviewing for jobs who are unable to
answer questions of the form, 'Oh, you're from UCSD.  What's Professor
so-and-so up to these days?'."</p>

<p>It took about six hours to get through talks from students working on Architecture, Bioinformatics, Systems, Graphics, Vision, Databases, Security, VLSI and more, and I'm not going to try to repeat any of the details, because frankly I'm numb. I will say that it was a great idea, and if you're a grad student and your department doesn't do something like this, you should start a tradition.</p>

<p>I will mention one thing: automatic detection and adaptation to network attacks is <a href="http://www.jacobsschool.ucsd.edu/news_events/releases/release.sfe?id=400">so hot right now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
