<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pacific Beach | michael-mccracken.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/blog/categories/pacific-beach/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-14T14:10:24-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael McCracken]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pacific Beach Night Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/07/pacific-beach-night-photos/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-10T18:20:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://michael-mccracken.net/2006/07/pacific-beach-night-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I took my camera with me on a late-night food run. On the way back, I stopped at the end of Felspar street and took some shots of the beach scene. My favorite two are already up at Flickr, but I thought I'd expand on them a bit here.</p>

<p>This is the end of Crystal Pier, which houses a hotel (you can see the last of the cabins on the left). I took a bunch of these shots, playing with the sensitivity and exposure. This was the longest - at ISO 200 and f/4.0, exposed for about 10 seconds.</p>

<p>Even with an f/1.4 lens, it was super dark and I had to focus manually. I set the camera on a post and used a 2-second delayed shutter to keep it still and out of my shaky hands.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaelmccracken/186275976/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/65/186275976_91ad85b289.jpg" alt="Crystal Pier" /></a></p>

<p>For comparison, here's a version taken at ISO 1600 :</p>

<p><img src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/IMGP0243.jpg" alt="Crystal Pier at ISO 1600" /></p>

<p>Even reduced in size, you can really notice the noise.</p>

<p>Here's a shot of a cleaning lady working at JRDN, the swank bar in the new Tower 23 hotel. Tower 23 doesn't really fit in in PB - it's way too self-conscious and preening of a place to feel natural in such a laid-back, seedy beach neighborhood. It seemed appropriate that on a Sunday night when the more relaxed established places like the PB Bar &amp; Grill and Longboards were really hopping, JRDN was closed - looking its ghostly best.</p>

<p>I should have remembered that I'd set the 2-second delay before I took this shot - I had the woman framed well, hit the shutter and wondered what was going on. Luckily, she stayed in the door frame, but I could swear it was a better shot just two seconds before.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaelmccracken/186275981/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/17/186275981_97a6aa094c.jpg" alt="Bar cleanup" /></a></p>

<p>Here's another missed shot opportunity, as she ducks behind the bar just as I find the right exposure and focus. I think the color in the other one makes it better, but the angle of the bar on this one has some promise. Shot through a couple of layers of glass, and manual focus - I'm sure it could be sharper if I'd kept trying.</p>

<p><img src="http://michael-mccracken.net/img/PB-20060710-3.jpg" alt="Bar cleanup 2" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
